<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Baptism on Church of The Holy Name of Mary</title><link>https://mary2.netlify.app/en/sacraments/baptism/</link><description>Recent content in Baptism on Church of The Holy Name of Mary</description><generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} Church of The Holy Name of Mary Permatang Tinggi</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mary2.netlify.app/en/sacraments/baptism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Baptism for Baby</title><link>https://mary2.netlify.app/en/sacraments/baptism/baptism-for-baby/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/en/sacraments/baptism/baptism-for-baby/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There are three sacraments that are the foundation of Christian life. These sacraments are: Baptism, Confirmation, and Eucharist. They are given in this order to bring about the full initiation of the new Christian life. These three sacraments together are called the Sacraments of Initiation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Holy Baptism is the first step to becoming a member of Christ and the Church. It is the basis of the whole Christian life, the gateway to life in the Spirit, and the door which gives access to the other sacraments. Through Baptism we are freed from sin and reborn as sons and daughters of God; we become members of Christ, are incorporated into the Church and made sharers in her mission…” (Catechism of the Catholic Church, 1213). We receive new life through baptism, washing away original sin and personal sins. This is represented by pouring of water over the head by a priest. The newly baptized receives grace and sealed with a permanent spiritual mark. Therefore, baptism can only be celebrated once.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="application-package-for-baby-baptism-new-born--6-years-old">Application package for Baby Baptism (New Born ~ 6 Years Old)&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Baptism Application Form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Birth Certificate&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Parent Workshop - An information session for priest to introduce Parents and God-Parents the meaning of the Holy Sacrament of Baptism and the Baptism Process.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The date of workshop will be one week prior to the Baptism. You will be notified after submit your application package.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Date: Twice Per Year (Easter Sunday and Holy Family Sunday)，&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Time: During 3PM Sunday Mass after Homily&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Registration: Please Submit Application package 3 weeks prior to the Date.)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="children-baptism-7--17-years-old">Children Baptism (7 ~ 17 Years Old)&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Registration - Through registration for RCIA for Children.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/img/sacraments/baptism/baptism4.jpg" >
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Application for Baptism (Baby)</title><link>https://mary2.netlify.app/en/sacraments/baptism/apply-for-baptism/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/en/sacraments/baptism/apply-for-baptism/</guid><description>&lt;pre>&lt;code>TODO
- form for baptism
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre></description></item><item><title>Rite of Christian Initiation of Adults (RCIA)</title><link>https://mary2.netlify.app/en/sacraments/baptism/rcia/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/en/sacraments/baptism/rcia/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="what-is-rite-of-christian-initiation-of-adults-rcia">What is Rite of Christian Initiation of Adults (RCIA)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The RCIA is a journey, set forth by the universal Church, for adult inquirers (seekers of faith) who desire to know and follow Jesus Christ and to become a member of the Catholic Church. The Rite prepares the adult inquirers with the aim to receive the Sacraments of Initiation – Baptism, Confirmation and the Eucharist.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="for-whom-is-rcia-intended">For whom is RCIA intended?&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Adults who are not baptised.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adults who were baptised in another non-Catholic Christian tradition.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Baptised adult Catholics who have not completed the Sacraments of Confirmation and Holy Eucharist.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="when-will-the-new-intake-for-20202021-commence">When will the new intake for 2020/2021 commence?&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Date: Sunday, 23 August 2021&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Time: 2.00pm-5:00pm&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Venue: ZOOM Conferencing&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="how-do-i-register-for-rcia">How do I register for RCIA?&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Kindly register online &lt;a href="#">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>or completing hard copies of the form (available from Parish Office) and returning the completed forms to the Parish Office.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="how-does-rcia-work">How does RCIA work?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>RCIA is a spiritual journey of faith. It is an exploration into the unknown that requires courage, persistence, and commitment. Rest assured, as St Augustine of Hippo puts it wonderfully, “To fall in love with God is the greatest romance; to seek him the greatest adventure; to find him, the greatest human achievement”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>RCIA is a spiritual journey of conversion and renewal of both heart and mind. We are informed, formed, and transformed through Jesus, with Jesus, and in Jesus. No one who sincerely comes to Jesus is not changed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The RCIA journey is communal and not individual. It is a journey which is never meant to be taken alone. The formation process takes place within the context of the community itself. The inquirers pray with the community and are prayerfully supported by it; they reflect on the Catholic faith within the context of the community, and they experience what it means to be a Catholic.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-is-expected-of-me">What is expected of me?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A desire to learn about the Catholic faith, and a certain level of commitment is expected in attending the 2-hour weekly session. Attendance is expected at the rites that comes with the journey as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ask questions. Ask any and all questions regarding your concerns about the faith.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spend time in prayer daily and to read materials handed out at each session. The Catholic Church is very rich in her teachings and practices, and it takes a lifetime to continually conform yourself to God.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last but not least, be open. Come with an open mind and heart. Be open and you will be surprised by God and the splendour of truth in the Catholic Church.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="my-schedule-doesnt-permit-me-to-attend-all-the-sessions-on-a-weekly-basis-what-shall-i-do">My schedule doesn’t permit me to attend all the sessions on a weekly basis. What shall I do?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Replacement classes will be held for those who are not able to make it for the particular session.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="i-hear-that-i-need-a-godparentsponsor-in-order-to-become-a-catholic-what-is-a-sponsor">I hear that I need a Godparent/Sponsor in order to become a Catholic. What is a Sponsor?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A Godparent/Sponsor is a baptised, confirmed, and practising Catholic, at least 16 years old, who acts as a spiritual companion and is willing to support as you in this RCIA journey, and serves as a spiritual mentor throughout your life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you know of someone who meets the above criteria, you can approach them to be your Godparent/Sponsor. If you don’t, the RCIA team will try to help you find a Godparent/Sponsor.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-the-godparentsponsor-do">What does the Godparent/Sponsor do?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Godparent/Sponsor journey with the you by attending the weekly RCIA sessions and also the rites that come with it, and he (or she) should care for you spiritual growth. Together with your Godparent/Sponsor, you discern your readiness to receive the Sacraments of Initiation (Baptism, Confirmation, and the Eucharist). Godparent/Sponsor should always be there to inspire, motivate, guide, and pray for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/img/sacraments/baptism/baptism3.jpg" >
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Application for RCIA</title><link>https://mary2.netlify.app/en/sacraments/baptism/apply-for-rcia/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/en/sacraments/baptism/apply-for-rcia/</guid><description>&lt;pre>&lt;code>TODO
- application form
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre></description></item></channel></rss>