<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Prayers on Church of Holy Name of Mary</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/tags/prayers/</link><description>Recent content in Prayers on Church of Holy Name of Mary</description><generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} Church of The Holy Name of Mary Permatang Tinggi</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/tags/prayers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bible Verses When We're Afraid!</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/project/bible-verses-when-afraid/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/project/bible-verses-when-afraid/</guid><description>&lt;p>The devil uses our flaws such as this one, to break us down even farther. The more we are filled with anxiety, the less we are filled with God’s word and spirit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dear friends, fear is a common experience especially during this Pandemic. Let read these bible verses everyday and be encouraged to trust God at all times. You can pick one of your favourite verse and write it down on a paper, stick it in your room so that you can memorise it and remind you that God is always in control.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Psalm 56:4&lt;/strong>
“When I am afraid, in you I place my trust.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1 Peter 5:7&lt;/strong>
“Cast all your worries upon him because he cares for you.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Psalm 55:23&lt;/strong>
“Cast your care upon the LORD, who will give you support. God will never allow the righteous to stumble.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Matthew 11:28&lt;/strong>
“Come to me, all of you who are weary and carry heavy burdens, and I will give you rest.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>John 16:33&lt;/strong>
“I have told you this so that you might have peace in me. In the world you will have trouble, but take courage, I have conquered the world.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>John 14:27&lt;/strong>
“Peace I leave with you; my peace I give to you. Not as the world gives do I give it to you. Do not let your hearts be troubled or afraid.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hebrews 13:5-6&lt;/strong>
“Let your life be free from love of money but be content with what you have, for he has said, &amp;ldquo;I will never forsake you or abandon you. Thus we may say with confidence: &amp;ldquo;The Lord is my helper, (and) I will not be afraid. What can anyone do to me?&amp;quot;”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Psalm 23:1-6&lt;/strong>
“The LORD is my shepherd; there is nothing I lack. In green pastures you let me graze; to safe waters you lead me; you restore my strength. You guide me along the right path for the sake of your name. Even when I walk through a dark valley, I fear no harm for you are at my side; your rod and staff give me courage. You set a table before me as my enemies watch; You anoint my head with oil; my cup overflows. Only goodness and love will pursue me all the days of my life; I will dwell in the house of the LORD for years to come.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Philippians 4:6-7&lt;/strong>
“Don’t worry about anything; instead, pray about everything. Tell God what you need, and thank him for all he has done. Then you will experience God’s peace, which exceeds anything we can understand. His peace will guard your hearts and minds as you live in Christ Jesus.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Proverbs 3:5-6&lt;/strong>
“Trust in the LORD with all your heart, on your own intelligence rely not; In all your ways be mindful of him, and he will make straight your paths.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Psalm 94:19&lt;/strong>
“When cares increase within me, your comfort gives me joy.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Psalm 34:4&lt;/strong>
“I sought the LORD, who answered me, delivered me from all my fears.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Exodus 14:13&lt;/strong>
“But Moses answered the people, &amp;ldquo;Fear not! Stand your ground, and you will see the victory the LORD will win for you today. These Egyptians whom you see today you will never see again.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Joshua 1:9&lt;/strong>
“I command you: be firm and steadfast! Do not fear nor be dismayed, for the LORD, your God, is with you wherever you go.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Isaiah 41:10&lt;/strong>
“Fear not, I am with you; be not dismayed; I am your God. I will strengthen you, and help you, and uphold you with my right hand of justice.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Isaiah 40:31&lt;/strong>
“They that hope in the LORD will renew their strength, they will soar as with eagles' wings; They will run and not grow weary, walk and not grow faint.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2 Timothy 1:7&lt;/strong>
“For God did not give us a spirit of cowardice but rather of power and love and self-control.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>James 1:2-4&lt;/strong>
“Consider it all joy, my brothers, when you encounter various trials, for you know that the testing of your faith produces perseverance. And let perseverance be perfect, so that you may be perfect and complete, lacking in nothing.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Isaiah 26:3&lt;/strong>
“A nation of firm purpose you keep in peace; in peace, for its trust in you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2 Thessalonians 3:16&lt;/strong>
“May the Lord of peace himself give you peace at all times and in every way. The Lord be with all of you.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>