<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Story of The Church of Holy Name of Mary on 峇冬丁宜圣母圣名堂</title><link>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/</link><description>Recent content in Story of The Church of Holy Name of Mary on 峇冬丁宜圣母圣名堂</description><generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>zh-Hans</language><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} Church of The Holy Name of Mary Permatang Tinggi</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Seven Sacraments</title><link>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/seven-sacraments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/seven-sacraments/</guid><description>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r2zKHSi54Uc" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="what-are-the-seven-sacraments">What are the seven sacraments?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The seven sacraments are &lt;a href="sacraments/baptism">baptism&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="sacraments/confirmation">confirmation&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="sacraments/communion">communion&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="sacraments/reconciliation">reconciliation&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="sacraments/anointing">anointing&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="sacraments/matrimony">matrimony&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="sacraments/holy-orders">holy orders&lt;/a>. They are divided into three categories: &lt;strong>&lt;em>sacraments of initiatio&lt;/em>n&lt;/strong>, &lt;em>&lt;strong>sacraments of healing&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> and &lt;em>&lt;strong>sacraments of communion &amp;amp; mission&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="where-did-the-sacraments-originate">Where did the sacraments originate?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the Bible, Christ gives his followers clear instructions on how to administer and receive each of the sacraments. This is seen through his work with the Apostles, healing the sick, parables, giving his body and blood to nourish our souls and forgiving sinners. The Church administers these holy sacraments as instructed, in order for all to worship God and receive His salvation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-the-sacraments-of-initiation">1. The Sacraments of Initiation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The three sacraments of initiation are baptism, confirmation and Eucharist. Each is meant to strengthen your faith and forge a deeper relationship with God. Baptism frees you from original sin, confirmation strengthens your faith and Eucharist allows you to taste the body and blood of eternal life and be reminded of Christ’s love and sacrifice.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="baptism">Baptism&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Baptism is the first sacrament where you become united with Christ and the Church – no other sacrament can be received without it. A priest performs this rite by immersing the baptismal candidate into water, therefore cleansing their original sin through water and the word. The candidate traditionally wears white garments, a candle is lit and they are anointed with sacred chrism. This is the first step in your relationship with God and Christ. Usually this takes place when the candidate is a baby, however, it’s never too late and you’re never too old to begin your journey with God. It’s common to have a baptism celebration with friends and family afterwards and give the child baptism keepsakes that will help them grow in their faith.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Go therefore and make disciples of all the nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit. Matthew 28:19&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>And it came to pass in those days, that Jesus came from Nazareth of Galilee, and was baptized of John in Jordan. And straightway coming up out of the water, he saw the heavens opened, and the Spirit like a dove descending upon him: And there came a voice from heaven, saying, Thou art my beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased. Mark 1:9-11&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>And they said, Believe on the Lord Jesus Christ, and thou shalt be saved, and thy house. And he took them the same hour of the night, and washed their stripes; and was baptized, he and all his, straightway. Acts 16:31, 33&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="confirmation">Confirmation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>This is the sacrament that follows Baptism as part of the initiation process with God and the Church, where the candidate receives the gift of the Holy Spirit and continues their journey with Christ. During Confirmation, the candidate is anointed on the forehead with chrism by a bishop. Since baptism typically happens when the candidate is a baby, confirmation is a great way for an older child to acknowledge that they still want to continue their journey with God and grow their relationship with Him. Celebrate your child’s confirmation by giving them a Bible with meaningful verses highlighted or cross as a daily reminder of God’s love.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Have I not commanded you? Be strong and courageous. Do not be terrified; do not be discouraged, for the Lord your God will be with you wherever you go. Joshua 1:9&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life. John 3:16&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus spoke again to the people, he said, “I am the light of the world. Whoever follows me will never walk in darkness, but will have the light of life.” John 8:12&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="communion">Communion&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Communion (or Eucharist) means thanksgiving. This is when Christ’s body and blood are offered and then received by the parishioner in the form of bread and wine. Christ during the Last Supper broke bread, ate it, gave it to his disciples and told them to eat it. Now the priest, through the words of consecration, blesses and administers the Holy Communion during every mass to remind followers that they are one with Christ. Food and drink nourishes our bodies ‒- Christ’s blood and body nourishes us spiritually.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Is not the cup of blessing which we bless a sharing in the blood of Christ? Is not the bread which we break a sharing in the body of Christ? Since there is one bread, we who are many are one body; for we all partake of the one bread. 1 Corinthians 10:16-17&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>While they were eating, Jesus took some bread, and after a blessing, He broke it and gave it to the disciples, and said, “Take, eat; this is My body.” And when He had taken a cup and given thanks, He gave it to them, saying, “Drink from it, all of you; for this is My blood of the covenant, which is poured out for many for forgiveness of sins. Matthew 26:26-28&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>They devoted themselves to the apostles’ teaching and to fellowship, to the breaking of bread and to prayer. Everyone was filled with awe at the many wonders and signs performed by the apostles. All the believers were together and had everything in common. They sold property and possessions to give to anyone who had need. Every day they continued to meet together in the temple courts. They broke bread in their homes and ate together with glad and sincere hearts. Acts 2:42-46&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="4-the-sacraments-of-healing">4. The Sacraments of Healing&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The two sacraments of healing are penance and anointing the sick. Penance allows for spiritual healing and absolution for people who have distanced themselves from God through sin. Anointing the sick allows for both physical and spiritual healing. When one falls seriously ill, a minister anoints them and prays over them, calling on Christ to strengthen and heal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="reconciliation">Reconciliation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>During the sacrament of Reconciliation (or Penance), one confesses their sins to God through a priest who forgives their sins by God’s mercy, and orders them to live a more faithful life through absolution. Confession is essential to cultivating and fruitfully living out the word of God. We’re not perfect people, even if we try to be. It feels so much better to confess some of those things you have done wrong and receive forgiveness. This helps us have a stronger relationship with God.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>No, I say to you: but unless you shall do penance, you shall all likewise perish. Luke 13:3&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>But if the wicked do penance for all his sins which he hath committed, and keep all my commandments, and do judgment, and justice, living he shall live, and shall not die. Ezekiel 18:21
Whoever conceals their sins does not prosper, but the one who confesses and renounces them finds mercy. Proverbs 28:13&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="anointing">Anointing&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>This sacrament is only bestowed upon those who are seriously ill or suffering, which then unites the inflicted with Christ’s passion. Anointing the forehand and hands of the person with chrism while a priest administers a special blessing is how this sacrament is received. This special blessing is one way to make the ill feel strengthened and more connected with God in both mind and body.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Is anyone among you sick? Let him call for the elders of the church, and let them pray over him, anointing him with oil in the name of the Lord. James 5:14&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>And they cast out many demons and anointed with oil many who were sick and healed them. Mark 6:13
This was to fulfill what was spoken by the prophet Isaiah: “He took our illnesses and bore our diseases.” Matthew 8:17&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="5-the-sacraments-of-communion--mission">5. The Sacraments of Communion &amp;amp; Mission&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Through matrimony and the holy orders, couples and the clergy promise to serve and build up the church community.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="matrimony">Matrimony&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Matrimony (or Marriage) isn’t just a union between man and wife. The devotion husband and wife have to each other, and to Christ, mirrors Christ’s love and service to the church. Through marriage, a couple promises to help build each other up in faith, serve each other and the church and be faithful to each other until death.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>For I know the plans I have for you,” declares the Lord, “plans to prosper you and not to harm you, plans to give you hope and a future.” Jeremiah 29:11&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>For husbands, this means love your wives, just as Christ loved the church. He gave up his life for her. Ephesians 5:25&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>So God created man in his own image, in the image of God he created him; male and female he created them. And God blessed them. And God said to them, ‘Be fruitful and multiply and fill the earth and subdue it and have dominion over the fish of the sea and over the birds of the heavens and over every living thing that moves on the earth.” Genesis 1:27-28&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="holy-orders">Holy Orders&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>This sacrament is for those who choose to become a priest, bishop or deacon. Through ordination, they are able to perform sacred duties and serve the church community. This is not a sacrament that everyone partakes in, rather it’s one that people feel called to by God.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>But you are a chosen race, a royal priesthood, a holy nation, a people for his own possession, that you may proclaim the excellencies of him who called you out of darkness into his marvelous light. 1 Peter 2:9&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Pay careful attention to yourselves and to all the flock, in which the Holy Spirit has made you overseers, to care for the church of God, which he obtained with his own blood. Acts 20:28&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I will give you the keys of the kingdom of heaven, and whatever you bind on earth shall be bound in heaven, and whatever you loose on earth shall be loosed in heaven. Matthew 16:19&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="living-out-the-sacraments">Living Out the Sacraments&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Receiving one of the seven sacraments is a life-changing moment where one truly experiences God’s salvation and Christ’s sacrifice. Events like first communion are exciting and deserve special gifts. Growing in faith doesn’t only happen through the sacraments, it happens through daily prayer and devotion. Tools like a rosary, Bible, prayer journal and cross can assist you in practicing your faith.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you know anyone about to partake in a sacrament or looking for tools to nourish their faith, consider blessing them in their journey with special religious gifts. It will be a keepsake that will stay with them as their faith continues to deepen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>峇冬丁宜圣母圣名堂历史(1838 -1993)</title><link>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/history/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/history/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="峇冬丁宜圣母圣名堂历史">峇冬丁宜圣母圣名堂历史&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>峇冬丁宜圣母圣名堂的历史, 是由峇都交湾天主教圣若翰堂开始。当时有众多华人和印度人来到那里, 从事农业, 槟城升天堂的神父便前来为他们服务, 圣若翰堂的领洗、婚配、坚振及疾葬礼记录都保存在峇冬丁宜圣堂。据最早的记录到最后的记录是1838 - 1890,共有五十二年。&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>1846年葛伦神父(FR. Couellon)在峇都教湾建了一间圣若翰堂,以照顾本地教友,并作为向威省发展的根据地。他更学会了淡米尔文;开始向印度人传教。&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>后来峇都交湾的农作物受到害虫侵蚀,教友们都逐渐向外地求发展,有些来到大山脚(直落卓坤),有些去到峇颜特拉(马章武莫),更有些来到峇冬丁宜。神父们也前来为他们服务,同时建立传教中心,这些就成了这三地教友最早的会所。&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>1850年德塞郎神父(Fr. Tisserang)由新加坡调来峇冬丁宜, 他也把他成立的圣玛利小修院迁来, 在这里开办了整十个年头。他建立了一座双层大屋,上面是神父和修士居住下面是讲道所和课室。南北更建了两座房屋, 充作学校, 一男一女 - 后来改为宿舍(Guru 屋)让远地的儿童(远至高渊、槟城)寄宿、读书、读道理。一切开销由教堂负责, 省吃俭用, 由专门的道理老师负责照顾和教导。&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>1859年毕尔神父(Fr. Pierre)来到峇冬丁宜, 他发现约有百位教友住在那里, 他们的农作物被害虫侵蚀。根据圣堂领洗部记录:1893 年九月十日布赫来神父(Fr. Bouheret)在峇冬丁宜, 为第一位教友儿童施行洗礼。这是峇冬丁宜圣母圣名堂最早的记录, 我们姑且把它算为这个堂区的生日。&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>1893年布神父在爪夷(Jam)申请到七百英亩土地供教友发展, 大约有五十位教友参加这个计划。1900 年布神父遽然去世, 并埋葬在本堂圣山。而住在大山脚的马神父(Fr. Bes)乃兼管峇冬丁宜教堂。1902年他在爪夷建立了一座小教堂, 供四周教友祈祷和参加弥撒用, 并向四周教外人士传扬福音。1905年一记录, 叙述有25人在那里领洗。后来这些土地都分给教友们。（据说入教者可得15 亩)。&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1909年墨立神父(Fr. Maury)被调来管理峇冬丁宜,1911年柏柴拉神父继位:1914 年薛麦克神父(3) Sect)正式来此视事,他在1919年离开峇冬丁宜,而于1921年再次前来掌管教务, 直到1937年,将近十余年, 是居留最久的一位本堂神父。他在任內, 于1928年兴建了现在的这座圣母圣名堂, 雄伟壮丽,至今已有六十年的历史, 除了钟楼尖塔外, 其他部分仍然坚固, 雄伟的直立在南大道旁边。薛神父在任时, 是本圣堂最发达和安定时期。当时的教友多以种植为生, 住在园丘內, 生活虽清苦, 但他们的信德都很坚强、很热心、很合作。当时的交通很不方便, 没有车辆, 只靠两条腿。虽远在爪夷、三巴央、茶山(茶山只有5家教友), 也一样走路到教堂参加弥撒。有教友去世时,他们从远处抬着棺木走到圣堂来,合作精可敬可佩。&lt;/li>
&lt;li>那时候, 神父要管理三个教堂, 三个主日才有一台弥撒。所以弥撒为他们来说是多么可贵。有者步行几十里路, 下山来参与, 而且着讲究,男的长裤、大衣、皮鞋(不准穿短裤), 女的一定要盖头巾。&lt;/li>
&lt;li>若遇夜晚有弥撒(如圣诞节)。教友在沿途中, 先把柳叶绑成一束束, 放在树下, 等回家时就利用这些柳叶火炬, 点燃照明回家的路。&lt;/li>
&lt;li>薛神父时期:工作多由神父一手包办, 道理老师协助。虽有成立「公教进行会」的组织, 只给神父咨询意见。&lt;/li>
&lt;li>建筑圣堂时, 教友全部参与工作, 有钱出钱, 有力出力。从河里挑水、打沙、敲砖等工作, 充分表现合作的精神。&lt;/li>
&lt;li>圣堂开幕时, 槟城大修院, 有一百多位修生, 神父们, 前来参加场面盛大热烈。&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1927年, 圣母玛利亚学校创立, 共有三班学生, 分为六年级。一位全职传道员, 居住在学校的一端, 为本地教友服务。历任校长为罗道云、黄静山、朱若翰(朱国书)、林运福。&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol start="6">
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>第二次世界大战, 教堂受影响很大, 日本人占领马来亚, 市区内很混乱, 有不少神父、修士逃来本圣堂避难。&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1949 - 1952 年许安东神父管理本堂, 他在1952 年四月在华都村建立了圣妇亚纳小圣堂。因为紧急法令的施行, 圣母玛利亚学校被迫关闭。政府成立峇冬丁宜村, 建立学校, 将人民集中, 新村内将近有八十多家教友。1954年陈芳荣神父(Fr. Thomas Chia) 在新村建立了一间小教堂和神父住屋, 并开始以华文举行弥撒。1969年陈神父重建了圣女玛达肋纳圣堂; 同年又建立了圣母圣名堂的神父住屋。陈神父是管理本圣堂最长久的第二位神父，他的住期是1952 - 1955; 1959 - 1970。&lt;/li>
&lt;li>在移民时期,政府曾徵用本堂一部分土地,建警察局。(现为老人院)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol start="7">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>1970年刘若石神父接掌本堂教务, 他曾继续陈芳榮神父的努力。在柔府村建立了一所圣若瑟小圣堂, 以照顾当地教友。1978年他领导教友庆祝圣母圣名堂五十金庆。教会比薛神父时期更繁荣和进步。绝大部分教友接受华文教育, 中间有一小部分受淡米尔文和英文教育。教会内习惯用华文, 但其他语文小组也受到照顾。&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>1984年熊光发神父调来本堂, 他曾改良圣堂的祭台, 拆掉圣堂两旁的门亭,而用其原料兴建了一座圣母亭。他也计划建立一座礼堂, 供教友集会、讲习之用, 但不幸染上癌症, 于1987年五月卅一日逝世, 安葬于本堂的坟场。&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>1987年康福堂副主教继態光发神父之位领导本堂教友,由两位大修院修士的帮助,调查了教友戶口, 同时, 按照教区的计划, 努力推行堂区革新, 并且提议修建礼堂以及发展圣堂的土地。由于神父短缺, 他也帮助三巴央和马章武莫的教友服务。更设法解決华都村和华都园教堂土地的问题。这期间, 成立了教理小组, 同时也购买了一架电脑来协助处理堂区革新的文件,和收集本堂的各种资料。&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>本堂自成立以来,共有以下神父和修会的圣召:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>一位教区司锋:陈汉忠神父。&lt;/li>
&lt;li>七位圣母会修士和一位学生。&lt;/li>
&lt;li>八位圣婴会修女。&lt;/li>
&lt;li>二位主母济传教会修女。&lt;/li>
&lt;li>一位加诺撒修女会初学生。&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol start="11">
&lt;li>本堂教友, 由于传统习惯, 具有服从的美德, 但缺乏自动的精神, 一切事情都信赖顺从神父,一切活动都要神父亲自推动才能进行。碰到一位魄力大, 推动力与组织力强并能与教友打成一片的神父, 教友就活跃起来, 信德日增, 热心团结合作, 否则就意气消沉。&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>因此,教会不能全面发展。梵二大公会议后, 教会鼓励教友养成自动自发的精神, 革除完全依赖神父的习惯, 而能自动地、积极地参与堂区的活动,这才是基督徒的真正精神 - 因为教会是我们的 - 我们是教会。&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="gallery">
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/history/gallery/Fr%20Michael%20Seet%20Silver%20Jubilee%20Celebration%20in1936%20%E4%B8%80%E4%B9%9D%E4%B8%89%E5%85%AD%E5%B9%B4%E8%96%9B%E9%BA%A6%E5%85%8B%E7%A5%9E%E7%88%B6%E5%BA%86%E7%A5%9D%E9%93%B6%E5%BA%86.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/history/gallery/_huffec35d434dda453ac75fc2266a6505a_45217_491fc799b05c130796855b6e9cce3f1a.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/history/gallery/Old%20church%20in%201928%20%E4%B8%80%E4%B9%9D%E4%BA%8C%E5%85%AB%E5%B9%B4%E6%9C%80%E6%97%A9%E5%BB%BA%E6%88%90%E7%9A%84%E6%95%99%E5%A0%82.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/history/gallery/_hu15b044ba83da0fd660abae27c11cff42_589108_0655a6a3e20310fdfeed9c7bd03565f0.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/history/gallery/The%20Opening%20Ceremony%20of%20the%20Church%20on%201.11.1928.%20Fr.%20Michael%20Seet,%20Bishop%20Dovals,%20some%20Priest%20and%20all%20Parishioners,%20in%20front%20of%20the%20newly%20built%20and%20blessed%20Church,%20Permatang%20Tinggi.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/history/gallery/_hu94f3746b022a8498cbf39ee8dbf39cc8_2106763_7805bf399ff49b953017362e6c956690.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/history/gallery/The%20original%20stairway%20was%20replaced%20by%20existing%20tarmac%20access%E6%97%A7%E6%9C%89%E7%9A%84%E7%9F%B3%E6%A2%AF%E5%B7%B2%E8%A2%AB%E7%9B%AE%E5%89%8D%E7%9A%84%E6%9F%8F%E6%B2%B9%E8%B7%AF%E5%8F%96%E4%BB%A3.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/history/gallery/_hue7c8131a28cb5dc0306e0a3427a2ecb4_2197240_39e87f3996ec9f9567fdf00b6bc7279d.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/history/gallery/certicate.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/history/gallery/certicate_hufc010e52171a1d11351aa82b0375f2a9_2442164_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="历史总结">历史总结&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="table-responsive">
&lt;table class="table table-hover table-borderless">
&lt;thead class="table-info">
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>年份&lt;/th>
&lt;th>峇冬丁宜圣母圣名堂百年大事录&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1893&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(11.9.1893)布赫来神父(Fr. Boaheret)为本堂第一位儿童行洗礼。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1893&lt;/td>
&lt;td>它也标志着这个教区 — 圣母圣名堂的诞生。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1900&lt;/td>
&lt;td>布赫来神父逝世,葬于本堂坟场。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1902&lt;/td>
&lt;td>马神父(Fr. Bes)在爪夷建立一座小教堂。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1927&lt;/td>
&lt;td>薛麦克神父(Fr. Michael Sheet)创立圣母玛利亚华文小学。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1928&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(2.11.1928)薛神父建立圣母圣名堂大教堂&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1952&lt;/td>
&lt;td>紧急法令, 居民迁至新村,圣玛利亚学校关闭。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>许安东神父(Fr. Anthony Khor)建立华都村圣亚纳小圣堂。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1954&lt;/td>
&lt;td>陈芳荣神父(FT. Thomas Chin)在峇冬丁宜村建小教堂。陈神父开始以华语作弥撒。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1966&lt;/td>
&lt;td>堂区理事会成立。林运福任主席。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1969&lt;/td>
&lt;td>陈芳荣神父重建峇冬丁宜村圣堂及神父楼。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(7月) - 在峇冬丁宜村施诊施药的德国修士离开本堂至怡保圣玛利亚医院。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(16.9.1969) - 圣玛达肋纳圣堂由槟城杨主教主持祝圣典礼。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(22.12.1969) - 王喜添修士宣发终身愿。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1970&lt;/td>
&lt;td>刘若石神父(Fr. Joseph Liu)任本堂。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1972&lt;/td>
&lt;td>王喜顺修士发终身圣愿。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1973&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(25.2.1973)陈汉忠神父晋升品。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1974&lt;/td>
&lt;td>刘神父渡假。陈汉忠神父(Fr. Paul Ching)暂代本堂。陈神父拆除大圣堂石级改建公路。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1975&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(13.4.1975)刘神父建柔府村圣若瑟小圣堂,杨主教祝圣。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1978&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(17.9.1978)大圣堂庆祝建堂50 周年金庆。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(17.9.1978)林运福兄弟荣膺教宗封赐长期卓越服务有全章及圣母会名誉会士。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(12 月)陈顺南修士发终身圣愿。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1980&lt;/td>
&lt;td>刘神父退休,林炳权神父(Fr. Martin Lam)接任本堂。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1982&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(12.9.1982)王美爱修女发终身永愿。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1983&lt;/td>
&lt;td>“救赎圣年”,本堂为朝圣圣堂之一。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1984&lt;/td>
&lt;td>熊光发神父(Fr. John Hiong)继任本堂。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(4.2.1984)林修女(Sr. Rosaland Lim)宣发终身圣愿。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(14.4.1984)陈汉蛮修士宣发永愿。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(5.6.1984)法蒂玛圣母像驾临,巡行峇冬丁宜村。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1987&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(31.5.87)能神父蒙主恩召。于3.6.87 在本堂举行隆重疾葬礼。吉隆坡总主教,模区薛主教,中柔曾主教亲临主持。出席的神父、修士、修女、教友等将近3千人,盛况空前。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(1.6.87)康福堂副主教继任本堂司铎。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(27.9.87)王喜顺修士发愿银庆。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1988&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(1.11.1988)大圣堂庆祝建堂60周年。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1989&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(13.4.1989)谢福华神父(Fr. Michael Cheah)晋升六品。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1990&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(15.4.1990)堂区革新正式开始。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(4.11.1990)陈武安修士发终身愿。王喜添修士发愿银庆。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(16.5.1993)礼堂举行动土礼。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(22.6.1993)赵通强修士宣发终身永。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(12.9.1993)庆祝开教百周年纪念。&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>教堂历代神父</title><link>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/past-pastor-priest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/past-pastor-priest/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="table-responsive">
&lt;table class="table table-hover">
&lt;thead class="table-info">
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>#&lt;/th>
&lt;th>名字&lt;/th>
&lt;th>司铎&lt;/th>
&lt;th>服务年份&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>布赫来神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV FR. P. BOUHERET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>10.09.1893 - 03.06.1900&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>麦斯神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. J. BES&lt;/td>
&lt;td>09.12.1900 - 19.03.1905&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>布洛撒神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. E. A. BROSSARD&lt;/td>
&lt;td>04.06.1905 - 19.12.1905&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>格尔满神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. HENRICUS GERMAN&lt;/td>
&lt;td>08.10.1905 - 12.09.1909&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>5&lt;/td>
&lt;td>墨立神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. N. MAURY&lt;/td>
&lt;td>24.10.1909 - 06.08.1911&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>6&lt;/td>
&lt;td>白柴拉神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. E. BERCHERAT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>30.04.1911 - 11.06.1914&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>7&lt;/td>
&lt;td>薛麦克神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. MICHAEL SEET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>13.09.1914 - 17.08.1919&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>8&lt;/td>
&lt;td>戴神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. J. M. DAY&lt;/td>
&lt;td>31.08.1919 - 29.03.1921&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>9&lt;/td>
&lt;td>薛麦克神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. MICHAEL SEET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>19.06.1921 - 16.12.1937&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>10&lt;/td>
&lt;td>麦克亨利神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. HENRY MICHAEL&lt;/td>
&lt;td>29.01.1928 - 10.11.1940&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>11&lt;/td>
&lt;td>洛郎神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. R. KAURENT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>23.01.1938 - 15.01.1939&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>12&lt;/td>
&lt;td>邓神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. J. TENG&lt;/td>
&lt;td>03.07.1938 - 02.02.1945&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>13&lt;/td>
&lt;td>陆神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. FRANCIS LEK&lt;/td>
&lt;td>11.02.1945 - 14.03.1948&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>14&lt;/td>
&lt;td>侯外格神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. FET. J. HOVERG&lt;/td>
&lt;td>08.02.1946 - 02.02.1945&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>15&lt;/td>
&lt;td>艾路布神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. N. A. ELOOGEBOOM&lt;/td>
&lt;td>20.04.1947 - 01.08.1948&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>16&lt;/td>
&lt;td>王保禄神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. PAUL WONG&lt;/td>
&lt;td>27.06.1948 - 18.09.1949&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>17&lt;/td>
&lt;td>许安东神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. ANTHONY KHAW&lt;/td>
&lt;td>26.09.1949 - 04.11.1952&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>18&lt;/td>
&lt;td>陈芳荣神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. THOMAS CHIN&lt;/td>
&lt;td>22.11.1952 - 25.09.1955&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>19&lt;/td>
&lt;td>王伯多神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. PETER WONG&lt;/td>
&lt;td>15.05.1955 - 21.04.1957&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>20&lt;/td>
&lt;td>能光发执事&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. JOHN HIONG&lt;/td>
&lt;td>24.04.1957 - 31.01.1958&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>21&lt;/td>
&lt;td>许化民神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. PETER HSIN&lt;/td>
&lt;td>21.09.1957 - 04.07.1958&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>22&lt;/td>
&lt;td>徐连文神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. PETER SU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>16.08.1958 - 03.01.1959&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>23&lt;/td>
&lt;td>陈芳荣神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. THOMAS CHIN&lt;/td>
&lt;td>08.03.1959 - 22.11.1970&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>24&lt;/td>
&lt;td>刘若石神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. JOSEPH LIU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>06.12.1970 - 21.04.1974&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>25&lt;/td>
&lt;td>陈汉忠神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. PAUL CHING&lt;/td>
&lt;td>05.05.1974 - 24.11.1974&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>26&lt;/td>
&lt;td>刘若石神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. JOSEPH LIU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>12.01.1975 - 02.12.1979&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>27&lt;/td>
&lt;td>刘炳权神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. MARTIN LAM&lt;/td>
&lt;td>17.02.1980 - 05.02.1984&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>28&lt;/td>
&lt;td>能光发神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. JOHN HIONG&lt;/td>
&lt;td>16.02.1984 - 05.02.1987&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>29&lt;/td>
&lt;td>康福堂副主教&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. MGR. RAPHAEL KANG&lt;/td>
&lt;td>11.03.1987 - SEPT.1996&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>30&lt;/td>
&lt;td>齐帝神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. NELSON CHITTY&lt;/td>
&lt;td>AUG.1995 - MAR.1996&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>31&lt;/td>
&lt;td>谢福华神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. MICHAEL CHEAH&lt;/td>
&lt;td>SEPT.1996 - FEB. 1998&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>32&lt;/td>
&lt;td>刘开祥神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. STEPHEN LIEW&lt;/td>
&lt;td>MAR. 1998 - JUN. 1999&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>33&lt;/td>
&lt;td>赵仲生神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. FRANCIS CHAO&lt;/td>
&lt;td>JULY 1999 - SEPT.2003&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>34&lt;/td>
&lt;td>悦恒力神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. HENRY RAJOO&lt;/td>
&lt;td>SEPT.2003 - 31.01.2005&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>35&lt;/td>
&lt;td>刘开祥副主教&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. MGR. STEPHEN LIEW&lt;/td>
&lt;td>01.02.2005 - OCT. 2010&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>36&lt;/td>
&lt;td>余金忠神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. SIMON EE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>01.08.2005 - 31.12.2010&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>37&lt;/td>
&lt;td>黄炳隆神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REV. FR. AUGUSTINE WONG&lt;/td>
&lt;td>JAN. 2011 - MAR. 2021&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>38&lt;/td>
&lt;td>雷神父&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FR. LOUIS&lt;/td>
&lt;td>APR. 2021 - PRESENT&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>教堂的故事</title><link>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="圣母圣名堂的建筑师">圣母圣名堂的建筑师&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>薛麦克神父生于1883年,他是圣母圣名堂的”建筑师”。他于1911年在华都牙也被祝圣为神父。他是圣母圣名堂1914-1919和1921-1937 本堂神父。他死于 18.6.1946 。根据他的回忆录, 他凭着手上仅有的$7000, 就充满信心筹备建堂。峇冬丁宜的教友只等到$2012。他也成功向远至曼谷和新加坡等到$1779 和$10219。峇冬丁宜的教友也贡献了400天的建筑劳工, 或是每家庭10 天。教堂是用石灰砖所建成。石灰砖是就地取的沙所做成。圣堂内的圣妇亚纳和圣若亚敬的彩色玻璃, 以及六个石灰的圣像是取自槟城的复活堂。在祭台上面的圣母无染原罪圣像是取自旧圣堂。薛麦克神父只买了圣心, 圣若瑟和黑圣母圣像。建堂一共用了$21816.64 薛麦克神父对赵有才先生有能力建造玫瑰大圆窗, 高祭台和旋转楼梯感到非常骄傲。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>教堂的三个大钟都有命名。它们是新加坡的 Chan Tek Yee 所捐献。薛麦克神父希望在经济的允许下, 后人可购买另两个不同音调的大钟, 这样在庆典之日就可听到美丽的钟声旋律。&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="当年建堂工臣">当年建堂工臣&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>已故赵有才是峇冬丁宜1928年建堂督工, 他当时只有23岁。当时的主教对他的成就非常赞赏, 就推荐他建了北海和太平的教堂和修女学校,其中有金马伦高原、大山脚、双溪大年、槟城、 安顺及怡保的教会学校。&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="教堂的建造设计">教堂的建造设计&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>圣母圣名堂是依据法国歌德式的设计所建成。歌德式的教堂通常有尖塔, 尖端, 精工的圣像, 有花纹的大窗口有如玫瑰窗口和彩色玻璃窗, 歌德式教堂的特色是它的耸立的高度代表到达天堂的愿望。所有的圣堂的构造都是本地设计和建造的, 比如那尖塔, 独特的旋转阶梯, 印有花纹的天花板以及玫瑰大圆窗。钟楼和尖塔共有九十尺高。它是用硬木和木板块建成。天花板是用胶性彩色涂上去的。&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="圣母圣名堂35周年庆典">圣母圣名堂35周年庆典&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>圣母圣名堂已有127年的历史。她是由薛麦克神父花三年多的时间建成。当年建筑圣堂时, 教友全部参与工作, 出钱出力, 充分表现合作的精神。&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="gallery">
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/FR%20Michael%20Seet%20%E8%96%9B%E9%BA%A6%E5%85%8B%E7%A5%9E%E7%88%B6.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/FR%20Michael%20Seet%20%E8%96%9B%E9%BA%A6%E5%85%8B%E7%A5%9E%E7%88%B6_hu3629cb56bf1c6e657bc75eba3c6f396c_75844_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/The%20Church%20Architecture%20j%E6%95%99%E5%A0%82%E7%9A%84%E5%BB%BA%E9%80%A0%E8%AE%BE%E8%AE%A1%201.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/The%20Church%20Architecture%20j%E6%95%99%E5%A0%82%E7%9A%84%E5%BB%BA%E9%80%A0%E8%AE%BE%E8%AE%A1%201_hu16685c591c287a0a3eab2c924f384260_875588_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/The%20Church%20Architecture%20j%E6%95%99%E5%A0%82%E7%9A%84%E5%BB%BA%E9%80%A0%E8%AE%BE%E8%AE%A1%202.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/The%20Church%20Architecture%20j%E6%95%99%E5%A0%82%E7%9A%84%E5%BB%BA%E9%80%A0%E8%AE%BE%E8%AE%A1%202_hue4a513f228094dba49ee08333d52f628_1061036_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/The%20Church%20Architecture%20j%E6%95%99%E5%A0%82%E7%9A%84%E5%BB%BA%E9%80%A0%E8%AE%BE%E8%AE%A1%203.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/The%20Church%20Architecture%20j%E6%95%99%E5%A0%82%E7%9A%84%E5%BB%BA%E9%80%A0%E8%AE%BE%E8%AE%A1%203_hu4df9aff0da66ddfd06b96305c107d2f4_2104048_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/The%20Church%20Architecture%20j%E6%95%99%E5%A0%82%E7%9A%84%E5%BB%BA%E9%80%A0%E8%AE%BE%E8%AE%A1%204.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/The%20Church%20Architecture%20j%E6%95%99%E5%A0%82%E7%9A%84%E5%BB%BA%E9%80%A0%E8%AE%BE%E8%AE%A1%204_hu425567937e7ae900c77421b8157bd95c_200898_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/interior.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/interior_hu14ca89d0b4b13d0c1bfe2d7fa40f99aa_739654_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/interior2.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/interior2_hu8750922f8ef2a92372d52c41d23aafd2_533452_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/interior3.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/interior3_hu85b65b9448b673d03c05d9deb26353a1_1462018_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/interior4.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/interior4_huc1c1751e933aac48fc834edbc2ea6911_1872508_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/interior5.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/interior5_hu5087743d77545a5cb2135c1cb91d7072_1887892_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/interior6.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/interior6_hu9ada99e440eefed0e4d7f70c11e2bed6_3140700_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/interior7.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/interior7_hub83918a3703125432662d176c05d0855_3849426_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/interior8.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/interior8_hue62cc077186cab16b439cdcfa1fda0fe_3773603_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/teoh%20yew%20chye%20-%20the%20contractor%20of%20the%20church.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/teoh%20yew%20chye%20-%20the%20contractor%20of%20the%20church_hu29f3f64c48d44ee74208e502abb86b52_168323_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/the%20church%20builders.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/publication/century-celebration/gallery/the%20church%20builders_hu912006195cf6e92d7d886ce85c3625d9_253901_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>