<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Donation on Church of Holy Name of Mary</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/tags/donation/</link><description>Recent content in Donation on Church of Holy Name of Mary</description><generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} Church of The Holy Name of Mary Permatang Tinggi</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/tags/donation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reach out to the poor</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/project/donation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/project/donation/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Happy those concerned for the lowly and poor; when misfortune strikes, the LORD delivers them. - Psalm 41:2&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>My dear brothers and sisters in Christ, The Covid-19 pandemic has caused much hardship throughout different level of society in particular for families and our parish has not been spared of it. In view of this, the parish is organizing some kind of assistance in the form of food items to be distributed to those families or individuals among our parishioners who are in dire need of these items. Those who are in need are requested to contact the parish office for further information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the same time, the parish priest is requesting for parishioners who are able, to donate food items, or cash donations for this cause in order to assist our sisters and brothers who are in need of assistance during this extraordinary times. Any kind of assistance is highly appreciated. Contact the parish office for further information. In the meantime, do keep those who are in need in prayers and continue to ask the Lord Jesus Christ to protect us from harm and an end to this pandemic. Stay safe &amp;amp; stay healthy, God Bless !&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yours in Christ,
&lt;em>&lt;strong>Fr Louis&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/img/project/donation/caritas-en.png" >
&lt;/figure></description></item></channel></rss>