<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sacraments on Church of Holy Name of Mary</title><link>https://mary2.netlify.app/sacraments/</link><description>Recent content in Sacraments on Church of Holy Name of Mary</description><generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} The Church of Holy Name of Mary Permatang Tinggi</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mary2.netlify.app/sacraments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anoiting</title><link>https://mary2.netlify.app/sacraments/anointing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/sacraments/anointing/</guid><description>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/img/sacraments/anointing/anointing.jpg" >
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="are-any-among-you-sick-they-should-call-for-the-elders-of-the-church-and-have-them-pray-over-them-anointing-them-with-oil-in-the-name-of-the-lord---james-514">&amp;ldquo;Are any among you sick? They should call for the elders of the church and have them pray over them, anointing them with oil in the name of the Lord. - James 5:14&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h4>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="what-is-anointing-of-the-sick">What is Anointing of the Sick?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Anointing of the Sick is given to the sick and those who are about to depart from this life. This Sacrament unites the suffering of an ill person with that of Christ. It enables forgiveness of their sins, comfort in their suffering, and restores the spirit. For the dying person, the sacrament is for the preparation for the passing over to eternal life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Sacrament is administered by a priest or bishop. A penitential rite followed by the Liturgy of the Word opens the celebration. Scripture awakens the faith of the sick and family members and friends to pray to Christ for the strength of his Holy Spirit. The priest lays his hands on the head of the sick person. He then proceeds to anoint, with the blessed Oil of the Sick, the forehead and hands of the sick person (in the Roman Rite). He accompanies these acts with the words, “Through this holy anointing may the Lord in his love and mercy help you with the grace of the Holy Spirit. May the Lord who frees you from sin save you and raise you up” (CCC, no. 1513) Holy Communion may be offered to the dying person.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="to-receive-anointing-of-the-sick">To Receive Anointing of the Sick&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you or someone you know are sick and would like to receive the Sacrament of the Anointing of the Sick, please contact our parish Father Louis at &lt;a href="tel:+6045887799">+6045887799&lt;/a> or book an appointment as soon as possible. There is no need to wait until the point of death if the illness is serious. The Sacrament may be repeated if the person recovers and becomes ill again, or if the person’s condition worsens.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Baptism</title><link>https://mary2.netlify.app/sacraments/baptism/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/sacraments/baptism/</guid><description>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/img/sacraments/baptism/baptism.jpg" >
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="go-therefore-and-make-disciples-of-all-nations-baptising-them-in-the-name-of-the-father-and-of-the-son-and-of-the-holy-spirit---matthew-2819">&amp;ldquo;Go therefore and make disciples of all nations, baptising them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em>&lt;strong>- Matthew 28:19&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/h4>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="what-is-baptism">What is Baptism?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There are three sacraments that are the foundation of Christian life. These sacraments are: Baptism, Confirmation, and Eucharist. They are given in this order to bring about the full initiation of the new Christian life. These three sacraments together are called the Sacraments of Initiation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Holy Baptism is the first step to becoming a member of Christ and the Church. It is the basis of the whole Christian life, the gateway to life in the Spirit, and the door which gives access to the other sacraments. Through Baptism we are freed from sin and reborn as sons and daughters of God; we become members of Christ, are incorporated into the Church and made sharers in her mission…” (Catechism of the Catholic Church, 1213). We receive new life through baptism, washing away original sin and personal sins. This is represented by pouring of water over the head by a priest. The newly baptized receives grace and sealed with a permanent spiritual mark. Therefore, baptism can only be celebrated once.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="baptism-in-the-church">Baptism in the Church&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Church of The Holy Name of Mary offers both &lt;a href="baptism-for-baby">baby&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="baptism-for-adult">adult/family&lt;/a> baptisms. To get started, please fill out the &lt;a href="baptism-form">baptism inquiry form&lt;/a> and our respective ministry will reach out to you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Communion</title><link>https://mary2.netlify.app/sacraments/communion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/sacraments/communion/</guid><description>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="https://mary2.netlify.app/img/sacraments/communion/communion.jpg" >
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="i-am-the-living-bread-that-came-down-from-heaven-whoever-eats-of-this-bread-will-live-forever-and-the-bread-that-i-will-give-for-the-life-of-the-world-is-my-flesh----john-651">&amp;ldquo;I am the living bread that came down from heaven. Whoever eats of this bread will live forever; and the bread that I will give for the life of the world is my flesh. - John 6:51&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h4>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="what-is-the-communion">What is the Communion?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There are three sacraments that are the foundation of Christian life. These sacraments are: Baptism, Confirmation, and Eucharist. They are given in this order to bring about the full initiation of the new Christian life. These three sacraments together are called the Sacraments of Initiation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First Communion is the first time the Eucharist, Christ’s Body and Blood, is received after the Sacrament of Baptism and Confirmation have been received. Through the priest’s holy prayers, bread and wine becomes the Body and Blood of Christ. After the First Communion, we are able to continually receive the sacrament. Whenever we receive Holy Communion (Eucharist) in mass, we are receiving the Sacrament of the Eucharist. In receiving the Body and Blood of Christ and participating in mass continually, we become united in one body with the Church.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="first-communion-at-church-of-the-holy-name-of-mary">First Communion at Church of The Holy Name of Mary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Our First Holy Communion is designed as a faith journey for children between the age of five to nine years old, and their parents to take part in it together. First Holy Communion preparation begins two years earlier, and concludes with First Holy Communion Mass in 20th October 2021.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For your child to receive First Holy Communion, he or she must be enrolled in our Religious Education classes. Our Religious Education class registration for 2020 is now closed. Please check back in September 2021 for registration for the 2021 class.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="rite-of-christian-initiation-of-adults-rcia">Rite of Christian Initiation of Adults (RCIA)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you’re an adult seeking to receive your First Holy Communion or thinking about becoming a Catholic, your next step is &lt;a href="rite-of-christian-initiation-of-adults.md">RCIA&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="preparation-for-persons-with-disabilities-oku">Preparation for Persons with Disabilities (OKU)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Church of The Holy Name of Mary and the Diocese of Penang understand that all Catholics have the right to participate in the sacraments. If you have a loved one (no matter what their age or disability is) who needs to prepare for any of the sacraments, please contact Father Louis at &lt;a href="tel:+6045887799">+6045887799&lt;/a> or book an appointment.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>