<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chapel on Church of The Holy Name of Mary</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/tags/chapel/</link><description>Recent content in Chapel on Church of The Holy Name of Mary</description><generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} Church of The Holy Name of Mary Permatang Tinggi</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/tags/chapel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Divine Mercy chapel at Taman Merak</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/project/divine-mercy-chapel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/project/divine-mercy-chapel/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a house purchased by Fr. Raphael Kang for the families who wanted a conducive place to pray. From the
beginnings of a prayer house, it developed into a chapel as the number of families that moved into the residential area increased. Plans to renovate the prayer house into a chapel were proposed. The renovation work to the chapel was started by Fr. Henry Rajoo who converted the corner lot house into a nice chapel named after Divine Mercy. It was officially blessed on 17.10.2004 by Bishop Antony Selvanayagam, Bishop of Penang.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>St Anne Chapel at Valdor Village</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/project/st-anne-chapel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/project/st-anne-chapel/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Chapel of St. Anne, Valdor Village dates back to the time of the emergency. A chapel was needed for the
parishioners to participate in the parish life. Fr. Anthony Khaw was responsible for constructing this chapel. It started with humble beginnings of a wooden structure on a large plot of land. As time went by, the chapel became too small to cater to the ever increasing number of Catholics. With time, the chapel became old and worn down. Fr. Raphael Kang was instrumental in raising funds to build a new chapel. The present structure is made of concrete.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>St Joseph Chapel at Juru Village</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/project/st-joseph-chapel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/project/st-joseph-chapel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Eight km away from the village of Permatang Tinggi, is Juru Village. Many Catholic families live here. To nurture their spiritual growth, a chapel was built so that masses could be celebrated on certain days of the month, especially during the feast day. Fr. Joseph Liu was instrumental in constructing this chapel, which was blessed by Rt. Rev. Bishop Gregory Yong.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>St Mary Magdalena Chapel at Permatang Tinggi Village</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/project/st-mary-magdalena-chapel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/project/st-mary-magdalena-chapel/</guid><description>&lt;p>The chapel dates back to the 1950s. To cater to the spiritual needs of the parishioners, the Chapel of St. Mary Magdalene was constructed in early 1954. When the number of families living in the village grew, the first chapel was found to be too small and could not cope with the increasing number of families. Fr. Thomas Chin constructed a bigger chapel through donations from the parishioners as well as help from the government.
Bishop Gregory Yong blessed the chapel on 16 September 1969. Additional renovations were done by the
subsequent parish priests. Fr. John Hiong built the bell tower and did some renovations to the chapel and
purchased new pews.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>St Paul The Hermit Chapel at Valdor Estate</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/project/st-paul-the-hermit-chapel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/project/st-paul-the-hermit-chapel/</guid><description>&lt;p>This chapel is a small shed with the statue of St. Paul the Hermit. Its construction dates back to 1953 during the time of the estate workers. It was at that time that the statue was placed in one of the sheds near the rubber estate. This shed served as a focal point for the spiritual activities among the estate workers. Although it is humble in it its origin, it serves the community well even till today.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>