<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sacraments on 峇冬丁宜圣母圣名堂</title>
    <link>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/sacraments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sacraments on 峇冬丁宜圣母圣名堂</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>zh-Hans</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} The Church of Holy Name of Mary Permatang Tinggi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/sacraments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Anoiting</title>
      <link>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/sacraments/anointing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/sacraments/anointing/</guid>
      <description>





&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://mary2.netlify.app/img/sacraments/anointing/anointing.jpg&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;are-any-among-you-sick-they-should-call-for-the-elders-of-the-church-and-have-them-pray-over-them-anointing-them-with-oil-in-the-name-of-the-lord---james-514&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Are any among you sick? They should call for the elders of the church and have them pray over them, anointing them with oil in the name of the Lord. - James 5:14&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-anointing-of-the-sick&#34;&gt;What is Anointing of the Sick?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Anointing of the Sick is given to the sick and those who are about to depart from this life. This Sacrament unites the suffering of an ill person with that of Christ. It enables forgiveness of their sins, comfort in their suffering, and restores the spirit. For the dying person, the sacrament is for the preparation for the passing over to eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sacrament is administered by a priest or bishop. A penitential rite followed by the Liturgy of the Word opens the celebration. Scripture awakens the faith of the sick and family members and friends to pray to Christ for the strength of his Holy Spirit. The priest lays his hands on the head of the sick person. He then proceeds to anoint, with the blessed Oil of the Sick, the forehead and hands of the sick person (in the Roman Rite). He accompanies these acts with the words, “Through this holy anointing may the Lord in his love and mercy help you with the grace of the Holy Spirit. May the Lord who frees you from sin save you and raise you up” (CCC, no. 1513) Holy Communion may be offered to the dying person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;to-receive-anointing-of-the-sick&#34;&gt;To Receive Anointing of the Sick&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know are sick and would like to receive the Sacrament of the Anointing of the Sick, please contact our parish Father Louis at &lt;a href=&#34;tel:+6045887799&#34;&gt;+6045887799&lt;/a&gt; or book an appointment as soon as possible. There is no need to wait until the point of death if the illness is serious. The Sacrament may be repeated if the person recovers and becomes ill again, or if the person’s condition worsens.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confirmation</title>
      <link>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/sacraments/confirmation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/sacraments/confirmation/</guid>
      <description>





&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://mary2.netlify.app/img/sacraments/confirmation/confirmation.jpg&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;all-of-them-were-filled-with-the-holy-spirit-and-began-to-speak-in-other-languages-as-the-spirit-gave-them-ability---acts-24&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;All of them were filled with the Holy Spirit and began to speak in other languages, as the Spirit gave them ability. - Acts 2:4&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three sacraments that are the foundation of Christian life. These sacraments are: &lt;a href=&#34;sacraments/baptism&#34;&gt;Baptism&lt;/a&gt;, Confirmation, and &lt;a href=&#34;sacraments/communion&#34;&gt;Communion&lt;/a&gt;. These three sacraments together are called the Sacraments of Initiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;receive-the-holy-spirit&#34;&gt;Receive the Holy Spirit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confirmation is the strengthening of the relationship with God. It seals our life of faith with Christ. Therefore, confirmation can only be celebrated once. It strengthens the Gifts of the Holy Spirit such as, wisdom, understanding, counsel, fortitude, knowledge, piety, and fear of the Lord, and the confirmed is able to be better witnesses of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one grows and matures in a natural family, so the Sacrament of Confirmation assists a person as he or she matures in the faith. God supports his son or daughter through the strengths of the Holy Spirit, and makes it possible for the person to witness to the faith through word and example. Confirmation makes a person a partner with God in the spreading of the Word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;high-school-confirmation&#34;&gt;High School Confirmation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For secondary school students looking to prepare for the Sacrament of Confirmation, please fill out the the confirmation inquiry form and our respective coordinator will be in touch with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;adult-confirmation&#34;&gt;Adult Confirmation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re an adult seeking Confirmation or thinking about becoming Catholic, your next step is Rite of Christian Initiation of Adults (RCIA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have an &lt;a href=&#34;../communion/rite-of-christian-initiation-of-adults&#34;&gt;RCIA program&lt;/a&gt; for both Mandarin and English speaking adults led by our own adult leadership. Candidates can prepare for receiving the Sacrament of Confirmation as well as the Sacrament of Baptism and the Sacrament of Communion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baptism</title>
      <link>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/sacraments/baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/sacraments/baptism/</guid>
      <description>





&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://mary2.netlify.app/img/sacraments/baptism/baptism.jpg&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;go-therefore-and-make-disciples-of-all-nations-baptising-them-in-the-name-of-the-father-and-of-the-son-and-of-the-holy-spirit---matthew-2819&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Go therefore and make disciples of all nations, baptising them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- Matthew 28:19&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-baptism&#34;&gt;What is Baptism?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three sacraments that are the foundation of Christian life. These sacraments are: Baptism, Confirmation, and Eucharist. They are given in this order to bring about the full initiation of the new Christian life. These three sacraments together are called the Sacraments of Initiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy Baptism is the first step to becoming a member of Christ and the Church. It is the basis of the whole Christian life, the gateway to life in the Spirit, and the door which gives access to the other sacraments. Through Baptism we are freed from sin and reborn as sons and daughters of God; we become members of Christ, are incorporated into the Church and made sharers in her mission…” (Catechism of the Catholic Church, 1213). We receive new life through baptism, washing away original sin and personal sins. This is represented by pouring of water over the head by a priest. The newly baptized receives grace and sealed with a permanent spiritual mark. Therefore, baptism can only be celebrated once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;baptism-for-adult&#34;&gt;Baptism for Adult&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re an adult seeking Baptism or thinking about becoming a christian, your next step is &lt;a href=&#34;rcia&#34;&gt;Rite of Christian Initiation of Adults (RCIA)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;TODO
### Baptism in the Church
Church of The Holy Name of Mary offers both [baby](baptism-for-baby) and [adult/family](rcia) baptisms. To get started, please fill out the [baptism inquiry form](baptism-form) and our respective ministry will reach out to you.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communion</title>
      <link>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/sacraments/communion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/sacraments/communion/</guid>
      <description>





&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://mary2.netlify.app/img/sacraments/communion/communion.jpg&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;i-am-the-living-bread-that-came-down-from-heaven-whoever-eats-of-this-bread-will-live-forever-and-the-bread-that-i-will-give-for-the-life-of-the-world-is-my-flesh----john-651&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am the living bread that came down from heaven. Whoever eats of this bread will live forever; and the bread that I will give for the life of the world is my flesh. -  John 6:51&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-the-communion&#34;&gt;What is the Communion?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three sacraments that are the foundation of Christian life. These sacraments are: Baptism, Confirmation, and Eucharist. They are given in this order to bring about the full initiation of the new Christian life. These three sacraments together are called the Sacraments of Initiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First Communion is the first time the Eucharist, Christ’s Body and Blood, is received after the Sacrament of Baptism and Confirmation have been received. Through the priest’s holy prayers, bread and wine becomes the Body and Blood of Christ. After the First Communion, we are able to continually receive the sacrament. Whenever we receive Holy Communion (Eucharist) in mass, we are receiving the Sacrament of the Eucharist. In receiving the Body and Blood of Christ and participating in mass continually, we become united in one body with the Church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;communion-for-children&#34;&gt;Communion for children&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our First Holy Communion is designed as a faith journey for children between the age of five to nine years old, and their parents to take part in it together. First Holy Communion preparation begins two years earlier, and concludes with First Holy Communion Mass in 20th October 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For your child to receive First Holy Communion, he or she must be enrolled in our Religious Education classes. Our Religious Education class registration for 2020 is now closed. Please check back in September 2021 for registration for the 2021 class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;communion-for-adult&#34;&gt;Communion for Adult&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re an adult seeking to receive your First Holy Communion or thinking about becoming a Catholic, your next step is &lt;a href=&#34;rite-of-christian-initiation-of-adults&#34;&gt;RCIA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;preparation-for-persons-with-disabilities-oku&#34;&gt;Preparation for Persons with Disabilities (OKU)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Church of The Holy Name of Mary and the Diocese of Penang understand that all Catholics have the right to participate in the sacraments. If you have a loved one (no matter what their age or disability is) who needs to prepare for any of the sacraments, please contact Father Louis at &lt;a href=&#34;tel:+6045887799&#34;&gt;+6045887799&lt;/a&gt; or book an appointment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holy Orders</title>
      <link>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/sacraments/holy-orders/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/sacraments/holy-orders/</guid>
      <description>





&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://mary2.netlify.app/img/sacraments/holyorders/holyorders.jpg&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;keep-watch-over-yourselves-and-over-the-whole-flock-of-which-the-holy-spirit-has-appointed-you-overseers-in-which-you-tend-the-church-of-god-that-he-acquired-with-his-own-blood---acts-2028&#34;&gt;Keep watch over yourselves and over the whole flock of which the holy Spirit has appointed you overseers, in which you tend the church of God that he acquired with his own blood. - Acts 20:28&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-life-of-service&#34;&gt;A Life of Service&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christ did not leave the Church without a sacrament of leadership and service. Through the various degrees of the Sacrament of Holy Orders, God raises up deacons, priests and bishops to serve, lead and govern the Church as a community of faith. As an ongoing sacrament, Holy Orders is God’s gift of assistance and strength for the preaching of the Word, the administration of the sacraments and the ministry of service leading to the holiness of all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-the-sacrament-of-holy-orders&#34;&gt;What is the Sacrament of Holy Orders?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who receive the sacrament of Holy Orders — as a deacon, priest or bishop — are consecrated in Christ’s name “to feed the Church by the word and grace of God.” These servants of God are ordained and given a special role in carrying out Christ’s mission and help Christians imitate Christ’s mission of love and justice. These roles include representing Christ, proclaim the Word of God, community building, missionary work, being servants, advocates for the poor, share Catholic social teachings, evangelize, and be witnesses of God. Priests and Bishops preside at Eucharist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vocations-in-the-priesthood-and-consecrated-life&#34;&gt;Vocations in the Priesthood and Consecrated Life&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in the vocations to the priesthood and consecrated life, please contact our parish Father Louis at &lt;a href=&#34;tel:+6045887799&#34;&gt;+6045887799&lt;/a&gt; or use &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;book an appointment&lt;/a&gt; for spiritual guidance and more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matrimony / Marriage</title>
      <link>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/sacraments/matrimony/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/sacraments/matrimony/</guid>
      <description>





&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://mary2.netlify.app/img/sacraments/matrimony/matrimony.jpg&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore a man leaves his father and his mother and clings to his wife, and they become one flesh. - Genesis 2:24&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sacrament of Matrimony celebrates the human capacity for love and total dedication, and serves as a witness to Christ’s love for the Church. It involves all aspects of life: mental, physical and spiritual. While beginning with a wedding service in the presence of God and the faith community, a husband and wife continue to confer the sacrament on one another whenever they offer themselves in the service of the other and the larger community. Thus, marriage is an ongoing sacrament. Should the marriage be blessed with children, the grace of the sacrament is there to strengthen the couple as parents as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We at Church of Holy Name of Mary are excited for you to grow in this love and understanding. This is one of the most exciting (and hectic) seasons in your life. Let us help you get ready for more than just the wedding day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;catholic-engage-encounter-cee&#34;&gt;Catholic Engage Encounter (CEE)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;../../talk/catholic-engage-encounter-penang&#34;&gt;CEE programme&lt;/a&gt; takes place in March, May August and October in 2021. Couples are encouraged to plan to complete the programme at least 6 months before the proposed date of their marriage. Couples will need to visit the Parish office or &lt;a href=&#34;form/ee/CEERegistrationForm_20210108.doc&#34;&gt;download&lt;/a&gt; the form online to complete the registration form and provide the necessary documents.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconciliation</title>
      <link>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/sacraments/reconciliation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/sacraments/reconciliation/</guid>
      <description>





&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://mary2.netlify.app/img/sacraments/reconciliation/reconciliation.jpg&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;19-repent-then-and-turn-to-god-so-that-your-sins-may-be-wiped-out-that-times-of-refreshing-may-come-from-the-lord---acts-319&#34;&gt;19 Repent, then, and turn to God, so that your sins may be wiped out, that times of refreshing may come from the Lord. - Acts 3:19&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-reconciliation&#34;&gt;What is Reconciliation?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of human weakness, the baptised often do not live up to their dignity as sons and daughters of God. The Sacrament of Reconciliation celebrates the forgiveness and mercy of God as the sinner humbly acknowledges and confesses his or her sins. The Sacrament also repairs or reestablishes a person’s unity with and membership in the Church. The priest represents both God and the Church, and speaks the consoling words of absolution in the name of both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;five-steps-for-reconciliation&#34;&gt;Five Steps for Reconciliation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the five steps to reconciliation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introspection&lt;/strong&gt;: examine our conscience with a prayerful heart and see how we have hurt others in our thoughts, words, and actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contrition&lt;/strong&gt;: admit and have remorse for your sins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change&lt;/strong&gt;: decide not to commit these sins again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confession&lt;/strong&gt;: Forgiveness-confess to a priest and receive absolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Penance&lt;/strong&gt;: Do the penance that the priest gives you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;TODO
### Confession Schedule
Confessions are held every half an hour before every Mass on Sundays and evening Mass on Saturdays. For the most up to date information, visit our Mass Schedule or [Bulletin](../../#home).


### Sacramental Prep
Reconciliation preparation begins with First Holy Communion Camp, normally two to three weeks before the conclusion of First Holy Communion Mass for the children, on 20th October 2021.

To receive First Reconciliation, your child must be enrolled in Religious Education classes and First Holy Communion (FHC) Camp. Our Religious Education class registration for 2021 is now closed. Please check back in September 2021 for registration for the 2022 class.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
