<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Confirmation on Church of The Holy Name of Mary</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/sacraments/confirmation/</link><description>Recent content in Confirmation on Church of The Holy Name of Mary</description><generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} Church of The Holy Name of Mary Permatang Tinggi</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/sacraments/confirmation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sacrament of Confirmation</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/sacraments/confirmation/sacrament-of-confirmation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/sacraments/confirmation/sacrament-of-confirmation/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>esus answered, “I am the way and the truth and the life. No one comes to the Father except through me. &lt;strong>- John 14:6&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Just as Baptism gives new life, Eucharist nourishes life, and Reconciliation restores life when it is broken, Confirmation strengthens that life by the gifts of the Holy Spirit (cf. CCC 1285). It is about strengthening what God has given, and continues to give, to his sons and daughters (cf. CCC 1302-1303).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Sacrament of Confirmation is not the Catholic equivalent to the Jewish bar mitzvah. Confirmation is not a “coming of age” celebration. True, most young people are just beginning to pass into early adulthood when they receive the sacrament. But Confirmation is not about coming of age. Reception of the Sacrament of Confirmation does not mark the end of formal religious education. We never outgrow a need for a deeper knowledge and appreciation of our faith.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Sacrament of Confirmation is not a rite of passage, nor a graduation from religion class, nor a ratification of a personal faith choice. Rather, it’s all about what God is doing for his beloved daughters and sons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And what is God doing? Strengthening the divine life which he gave at Baptism, nourishing us in the Eucharist, and reconciling with us in Penance. Why? So that the individual can better defend and witness to the faith through the gifts and workings of the Holy Spirit. And there are—and will be—many situations where we are called upon to defend and witness to our faith. And we need all the help we can get!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-role-does-the-holy-spirit-play-in-the-sacrament-of-confirmation">What role does the Holy Spirit play in the Sacrament of Confirmation?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the Sacrament of Confirmation, the Holy Spirit completes the grace of baptism and offers the newly confirmed strength as a true witness of Christ. Thus, the newly confirmed is “more strictly obliged to spread and defend the faith by word and deed” (cf. CCC, 1285). Thus, the Holy Spirit completes what was begun at baptism.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="would-it-be-better-to-confirm-people-when-they-are-adults-and-can-make-their-own-choices">Would it be better to confirm people when they are adults and can make their own choices?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Canon Law states that, except when there is a danger of death, anyone who is baptised and has the use of reason, is properly instructed and disposed, and is able to renew their baptismal commitment, is able to be confirmed. The same code states that the proper age for reception of the sacrament is at the age of reason, unless the episcopal conference decides differently (cf. CIC, can. 891).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perhaps the requirement that one be “properly disposed” is the key to when the sacrament is received. Proper disposition refers to the recipient’s willingness to cooperate with the gifts of the sacrament, which can happen at almost any age. But nowhere is the sacrament described as a ratification of the recipient’s choice or decision about the faith. Rather, it is the gifts of the Spirit offered to give the recipient the courage and strength to witness and serve—two responsibilities implied in baptism—which are the grace and focus of the sacrament.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thus, it is important not to view the Sacrament of Confirmation as a rite of passage, a ratification of a personal choice, or a graduation from religious instruction. Rather, it is to be viewed, as are all of the sacraments, as a distinctive working of God in a person’s life.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-does-this-sacrament-benefit-us-in-our-adult-lives-as-catholics">How does this sacrament benefit us in our adult lives as Catholics?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Sacrament of Confirmation helps a person remain faithful to his or her baptismal commitment to witness to Christ and to serve others. The gifts of the Holy Spirit associated with Confirmation are strengths (or virtues) that Christian living requires if it is to be fruitful and complete. Thus wisdom, understanding, knowledge, counsel, fortitude, piety, and fear of the Lord, are divine aids to Christian living without which, fulfilling one’s baptismal calling would be far more difficult, if not impossible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perhaps we don’t recognise these qualities as gifts of strength because they have become a part of our Christian living and appear quite natural — a fact that affirms how closely the Holy Spirit works with us.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/img/sacraments/confirmation/confirmation2.jpg" >
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Rite of Christian Initiation of Adults (RCIA)</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/sacraments/confirmation/rite-of-christian-initiation-of-adults/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/sacraments/confirmation/rite-of-christian-initiation-of-adults/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="what-is-rite-of-christian-initiation-of-adults-rcia">What is Rite of Christian Initiation of Adults (RCIA)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The RCIA is a journey, set forth by the universal Church, for adult inquirers (seekers of faith) who desire to know and follow Jesus Christ and to become a member of the Catholic Church. The Rite prepares the adult inquirers with the aim to receive the Sacraments of Initiation – Baptism, Confirmation and the Eucharist.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="for-whom-is-rcia-intended">For whom is RCIA intended?&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Adults who are not baptised.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adults who were baptised in another non-Catholic Christian tradition.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Baptised adult Catholics who have not completed the Sacraments of Confirmation and Holy Eucharist.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="when-will-the-new-intake-for-20202021-commence">When will the new intake for 2020/2021 commence?&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Date: Sunday, 23 August 2021&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Time: 2.00pm-5:00pm&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Venue: ZOOM Conferencing&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="how-do-i-register-for-rcia">How do I register for RCIA?&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Kindly register online here.
&amp;amp; Completing hard copies of the form (available from Parish Office) and returning the completed forms to the Parish Office.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="how-does-rcia-work">How does RCIA work?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>RCIA is a spiritual journey of faith. It is an exploration into the unknown that requires courage, persistence, and commitment. Rest assured, as St Augustine of Hippo puts it wonderfully, “To fall in love with God is the greatest romance; to seek him the greatest adventure; to find him, the greatest human achievement”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>RCIA is a spiritual journey of conversion and renewal of both heart and mind. We are informed, formed, and transformed through Jesus, with Jesus, and in Jesus. No one who sincerely comes to Jesus is not changed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The RCIA journey is communal and not individual. It is a journey which is never meant to be taken alone. The formation process takes place within the context of the community itself. The inquirers pray with the community and are prayerfully supported by it; they reflect on the Catholic faith within the context of the community, and they experience what it means to be a Catholic.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-is-expected-of-me">What is expected of me?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A desire to learn about the Catholic faith, and a certain level of commitment is expected in attending the 2-hour weekly session. Attendance is expected at the rites that comes with the journey as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ask questions. Ask any and all questions regarding your concerns about the faith.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spend time in prayer daily and to read materials handed out at each session. The Catholic Church is very rich in her teachings and practices, and it takes a lifetime to continually conform yourself to God.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last but not least, be open. Come with an open mind and heart. Be open and you will be surprised by God and the splendour of truth in the Catholic Church.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="my-schedule-doesnt-permit-me-to-attend-all-the-sessions-on-a-weekly-basis-what-shall-i-do">My schedule doesn’t permit me to attend all the sessions on a weekly basis. What shall I do?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Replacement classes will be held for those who are not able to make it for the particular session.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="i-hear-that-i-need-a-godparentsponsor-in-order-to-become-a-catholic-what-is-a-sponsor">I hear that I need a Godparent/Sponsor in order to become a Catholic. What is a Sponsor?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A Godparent/Sponsor is a baptised, confirmed, and practising Catholic, at least 16 years old, who acts as a spiritual companion and is willing to support as you in this RCIA journey, and serves as a spiritual mentor throughout your life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you know of someone who meets the above criteria, you can approach them to be your Godparent/Sponsor. If you don’t, the RCIA team will try to help you find a Godparent/Sponsor.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-does-the-godparentsponsor-do">What does the Godparent/Sponsor do?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Godparent/Sponsor journey with the you by attending the weekly RCIA sessions and also the rites that come with it, and he (or she) should care for you spiritual growth. Together with your Godparent/Sponsor, you discern your readiness to receive the Sacraments of Initiation (Baptism, Confirmation, and the Eucharist). Godparent/Sponsor should always be there to inspire, motivate, guide, and pray for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/img/sacraments/communion/rcia2.jpg" >
&lt;/figure></description></item></channel></rss>