<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chapel on 峇冬丁宜圣母圣名堂</title>
    <link>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/tags/chapel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chapel on 峇冬丁宜圣母圣名堂</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>zh-Hans</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} The Church of Holy Name of Mary Permatang Tinggi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/tags/chapel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>St Anne Chapel at Valdor Village</title>
      <link>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/project/st-mary-magdalena-chapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/project/st-mary-magdalena-chapel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;St. Anne Chapel was built on 1952 during the Emergency Act by Fr. Anthony Khow. Feast day is on 26 July and it is always celebrated a week later due to similar celebration in Bukit Mertajam.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>St Joseph Chapel at Juru Village</title>
      <link>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/project/st-joseph-chapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/project/st-joseph-chapel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;St. Joseph chapel was built by Fr. Joseph Liu and blessed by Bishop Gregory Yong on 13 April 1975. Annual feast day is on 1 May.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>St Mary Magdalena Chapel at Permatang Tinggi Village</title>
      <link>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/project/st-anne-chapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/project/st-anne-chapel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These were over 80 Catholic families in Permatang Tinggi New Village during the Emergency. In 1954, Fr. Thomas Chin built a small chapel. As the chapel was too small for the increasing number of parishioners. It was rebuilt into a bigger chapel with the parishioners donations and government fund. The blessing of the New Chapel was officiated by Bishop Gregory Yong on 16 September 1969.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1986, Fr. John Hsiong built a bell tower, the balance of money was used to renovate the altar and purchase of new pews. Annual feast day is on 22 July.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>St Paul The Hermit Chapel at Valdor Estate</title>
      <link>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/project/st-paul-the-hermit-chapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/zh/project/st-paul-the-hermit-chapel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It started during the construction of Estate Workers&#39; Quarter on 1953, some Tamil speaking parishioners placed a statue of St. Paul the Hermit at near by rubber estate. A shed was erected during 1970s. It is a hope if every parishioners in Valdor Estate that a chapel be built in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
