<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bible verse on Church of The Holy Name of Mary</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/categories/bible-verse/</link><description>Recent content in Bible verse on Church of The Holy Name of Mary</description><generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} Church of The Holy Name of Mary Permatang Tinggi</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/categories/bible-verse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Matthew 8:18-22</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-18-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-18-22/</guid><description>&lt;figure >
&lt;audio id="player" controls>
&lt;source src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/audio/en/matthew8-18-22.mp3" type="audio/mp3">
&lt;/audio>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="gospel">Gospel&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus saw the crowd around him, he gave orders to cross to the other side of the lake. Then a teacher of the law came to him and said, “Teacher, I will follow you wherever you go.” Jesus replied, “Foxes have dens and birds have nests, but the Son of Man has no place to lay his head.” Another disciple said to him, “Lord, first let me go and bury my father.” But Jesus told him, “Follow me, and let the dead bury their own dead.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Bishop and Martyr. St Polycarp was instructed in the faith by St John the Apostle. He, Polycarp instructed St Irenaeus who became a Bishop in France. He is an early Church Father. God called Irenaeus to uphold the revealed truth of the faith and bring peace to the Church.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are you called to serve the Lord? The marching order is intimidating. Don&amp;rsquo;t waste time about who died and burial rites. “Follow me, and let the dead bury their dead.” On another occasion, Jesus commanded the disciples: &amp;ldquo;More than anything else, put God’s work first and do what he wants. Then the other things will be yours as well.&amp;rdquo; (Matthew 6: 33 CEV).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>St Irenaeus, Bishop and Martyr and Father of the Church did not play games with the truths of the holy Faith. He studied what Christ our Teacher handed down to us. For example, the Eucharist. His bold, clear and unambiguous teaching was respected even by foes and he brought peace to the Church. One of Irenaeus famous quotes is: &amp;ldquo;The glory of God is man fully alive.&amp;rdquo; God is glorified when we develop our talents to the utmost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I want you to speak to the faithful of the Holy Mass as a true sacrifice. They have forgotten this. No one thinks any more to tell them that the action of the Eucharist renews My sacrifice upon the Cross, and that I am present upon the altar as upon the Cross, as both Priest and Victim. It is the whole of My sacrifice of love that unfolds before their eyes. You must tell them this.&amp;rdquo; (Jesus to a Benedictine mystic: IN SINU JESU).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By the prayers of St Irenaeus, may God renew our faith and love for the Most Holy Eucharist.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mark 8:21-43</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/mark8-21-43/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/mark8-21-43/</guid><description>&lt;figure >
&lt;audio id="player" controls>
&lt;source src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/audio/en/mark8-21-43.mp3" type="audio/mp3">
&lt;/audio>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="gospel">Gospel&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus had again crossed over by boat to the other side of the lake, a large crowd gathered around him while he was by the lake. Then one of the synagogue leaders, named Jairus, came, and when he saw Jesus, he fell at his feet. He pleaded earnestly with him, “My little daughter is dying. Please come and put your hands on her so that she will be healed and live.” So Jesus went with him.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A large crowd followed and pressed around him. And a woman was there who had been subject to bleeding for twelve years. She had suffered a great deal under the care of many doctors and had spent all she had, yet instead of getting better she grew worse. When she heard about Jesus, she came up behind him in the crowd and touched his cloak, because she thought, “If I just touch his clothes, I will be healed.” Immediately her bleeding stopped and she felt in her body that she was freed from her suffering.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>At once Jesus realized that power had gone out from him. He turned around in the crowd and asked, “Who touched my clothes?” “You see the people crowding against you,” his disciples answered, “and yet you can ask, ‘Who touched me?’ ” But Jesus kept looking around to see who had done it. Then the woman, knowing what had happened to her, came and fell at his feet and, trembling with fear, told him the whole truth. He said to her, “Daughter, your faith has healed you. Go in peace and be freed from your suffering.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>While Jesus was still speaking, some people came from the house of Jairus, the synagogue leader. “Your daughter is dead,” they said. “Why bother the teacher anymore?” Overhearing what they said, Jesus told him, “Don’t be afraid; just believe.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>He did not let anyone follow him except Peter, James and John the brother of James. When they came to the home of the synagogue leader, Jesus saw a commotion, with people crying and wailing loudly. He went in and said to them, “Why all this commotion and wailing? The child is not dead but asleep.” But they laughed at him.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>After he put them all out, he took the child’s father and mother and the disciples who were with him, and went in where the child was. He took her by the hand and said to her, “Talitha koum!” (which means “Little girl, I say to you, get up!”). Immediately the girl stood up and began to walk around (she was twelve years old). At this they were completely astonished. He gave strict orders not to let anyone know about this, and told them to give her something to eat.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="sermon">Sermon&lt;/h3>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1PKmLY7F94E" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Gospel for the 13th Sunday in Ordinary Time contains two important stories about the importance of faith in healing:
Woman with a Hemorrhage and Jairus’s Daughter. The afflicted woman and Jairus had heard about Jesus before they sought Him out and encountered the Lord.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jesus praised the faith of the woman. “Daughter, your faith has saved you. Go in peace and be cured of your affliction.” When the crowd wanted to pour cold water on the faith of Jairus, Jesus said to him: “Do not be afraid; just have faith.” I like how one translation renders this: &amp;ldquo;Fear is useless. What is needed is trust.&amp;rdquo; When Jairus heard this, his faith was strengthened. Jesus went into the house where He took the child by the hand and said to her, “Talitha koum,” which means, “Little girl, I say to you, arise!” The girl, a child of twelve, arose immediately and walked around. At that they were utterly astounded.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your trust in Jesus is in direct proportion to your awareness of who He is and how much He has done for you.
&amp;ldquo;Love Me and believe in My unconditional love for you. Trust Me. Show Me that you have confidence in My merciful goodness, especially when you experience weakness, or shame, or fear, and I will renew the grace of My love in your heart. I will uphold you with the gift of My unfailing presence.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Matthew 8:5-17</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-5-17/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-5-17/</guid><description>&lt;figure >
&lt;audio id="player" controls>
&lt;source src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/audio/en/matthew8-5-17.mp3" type="audio/mp3">
&lt;/audio>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="gospel">Gospel&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus had entered Capernaum, a centurion came to him, asking for help. “Lord,” he said, “my servant lies at home paralyzed, suffering terribly.” Jesus said to him, “Shall I come and heal him?” The centurion replied, “Lord, I do not deserve to have you come under my roof. But just say the word, and my servant will be healed. For I myself am a man under authority, with soldiers under me. I tell this one, ‘Go,’ and he goes; and that one, ‘Come,’ and he comes. I say to my servant, ‘Do this,’ and he does it.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus heard this, he was amazed and said to those following him, “Truly I tell you, I have not found anyone in Israel with such great faith. I say to you that many will come from the east and the west, and will take their places at the feast with Abraham, Isaac and Jacob in the kingdom of heaven. But the subjects of the kingdom will be thrown outside, into the darkness, where there will be weeping and gnashing of teeth.” Then Jesus said to the centurion, “Go! Let it be done just as you believed it would.” And his servant was healed at that moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus came into Peter’s house, he saw Peter’s mother-in-law lying in bed with a fever. He touched her hand and the fever left her, and she got up and began to wait on him. When evening came, many who were demon-possessed were brought to him, and he drove out the spirits with a word and healed all the sick. This was to fulfill what was spoken through the prophet Isaiah: “He took up our infirmities and bore our diseases.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="sermon">Sermon&lt;/h3>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/leaA9RqU3l4" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>What kind of expectant faith and trust does the Lord Jesus want you to place in him? In Jesus' time the Jews hated the Romans because they represented everything the Jews stood against - including pagan beliefs and idol worship, immoral practices such as abortion and infanticide, and the suppression of the Israelites' claim to be a holy nation governed solely by God&amp;rsquo;s law. It must have been a remarkable sight for the Jewish residents of Capernaum to see Jesus conversing with an officer of the Roman army.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="the-power-to-command-with-trust-and-respect">The power to command with trust and respect&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Why did Jesus not only warmly receive a Roman centurion but praise him as a model of faith and confidence in God? In the Roman world the position of centurion was very important. He was an officer in charge of a hundred soldiers. In a certain sense, he was the backbone of the Roman army, the cement which held the army together. Polybius, an ancient write, describes what a centurion should be: &amp;ldquo;They must not be so much venturesome seekers after danger as men who can command, steady in action, and reliable; they ought not to be over-anxious to rush into the fight, but when hard pressed, they must be ready to hold their ground, and die at their posts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="faith-in-jesus-authority-over-sickness-and-power-to-heal">Faith in Jesus' authority over sickness and power to heal&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The centurion who approached Jesus was not only courageous, but faith-filled as well. He risked the ridicule of his Roman cronies (close friends of someone in a powerful position) by seeking help from a traveling preacher from Galilee, as well as mockery from the Jews who despised their Roman overlords. Nonetheless, the centurion approached Jesus with great respect and confidence. He was an extraordinary man because he loved his slave. In the Roman world slaves were treated as property and like animals rather than people. The centurion was an extraordinary man of faith and love. He wanted Jesus to heal his beloved slave. Jesus commends him for his faith and immediately grants him his request. Are you willing to suffer mockery or ridicule in the practice of your faith? And when you in need of help, do you approach the Lord Jesus with expectant faith and trust?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Heavenly Father, you sent us your only begotten Son, our Lord Jesus Christ, to set us free from sin, pride, and Satan&amp;rsquo;s lies. Set me free from doubt and pride so that I may trust in your all-powerful word of truth and life. Strengthen me in faith, hope, and love so that I may always think, act and serve in the power of your merciful kindness and compassion towards all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Matthew 8:1-4</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-1-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-1-4/</guid><description>&lt;figure >
&lt;audio id="player" controls>
&lt;source src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/audio/en/matthew8-1-4.mp3" type="audio/mp3">
&lt;/audio>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="gospel">Gospel&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus came down from the mountainside, large crowds followed him. A man with leprosy came and knelt before him and said, “Lord, if you are willing, you can make me clean.” Jesus reached out his hand and touched the man. “I am willing,” he said. “Be clean!” Immediately he was cleansed of his leprosy. Then Jesus said to him, “See that you don’t tell anyone. But go, show yourself to the priest and offer the gift Moses commanded, as a testimony to them.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In our key Scripture for today, Jesus healed a leper instantly by touching him. Contrary to the beliefs of the time, Jesus did not contract any ritual uncleanness. Leprosy was one of the diseases that was considered physically and spiritually ugly and excludes the sufferer from the community and most importantly, from the houses of worship.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mortal sin is analogous to leprosy. It is God&amp;rsquo;s merciful Providence that humans do not see the soul.
The One who touched the lepers and healed them is still among us. He heals every day the most important ailment of man, sin. He does this through the Sacrament of Penance. A good Confession restores the soul fully to sanctifying grace. Sanctifying grace is the life of God in the soul. The soul becomes once again the home of the Holy Spirit. Who cannot be moved by the words of Jesus below to a Benedictine mystic?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>