<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sacraments on Church of Holy Name of Mary</title>
    <link>https://mary2.netlify.app/tags/sacraments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sacraments on Church of Holy Name of Mary</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} The Church of Holy Name of Mary Permatang Tinggi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://mary2.netlify.app/tags/sacraments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Baptism</title>
      <link>https://mary2.netlify.app/sacraments/baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/sacraments/baptism/</guid>
      <description>





&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://mary2.netlify.app/img/sacraments/baptism/baptism.jpg&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;go-therefore-and-make-disciples-of-all-nations-baptising-them-in-the-name-of-the-father-and-of-the-son-and-of-the-holy-spirit---matthew-2819&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Go therefore and make disciples of all nations, baptising them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- Matthew 28:19&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-baptism&#34;&gt;What is Baptism?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three sacraments that are the foundation of Christian life. These sacraments are: Baptism, Confirmation, and Eucharist. They are given in this order to bring about the full initiation of the new Christian life. These three sacraments together are called the Sacraments of Initiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy Baptism is the first step to becoming a member of Christ and the Church. It is the basis of the whole Christian life, the gateway to life in the Spirit, and the door which gives access to the other sacraments. Through Baptism we are freed from sin and reborn as sons and daughters of God; we become members of Christ, are incorporated into the Church and made sharers in her mission…” (Catechism of the Catholic Church, 1213). We receive new life through baptism, washing away original sin and personal sins. This is represented by pouring of water over the head by a priest. The newly baptized receives grace and sealed with a permanent spiritual mark. Therefore, baptism can only be celebrated once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;baptism-in-the-church&#34;&gt;Baptism in the Church&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Church of The Holy Name of Mary offers both &lt;a href=&#34;baptism-for-baby&#34;&gt;baby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;baptism-for-adult&#34;&gt;adult/family&lt;/a&gt; baptisms. To get started, please fill out the &lt;a href=&#34;baptism-form&#34;&gt;baptism inquiry form&lt;/a&gt; and our respective ministry will reach out to you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
