<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Authors on Church of Holy Name of Mary</title><link>https://mary2.netlify.app/authors/</link><description>Recent content in Authors on Church of Holy Name of Mary</description><generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} The Church of Holy Name of Mary Permatang Tinggi</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mary2.netlify.app/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://mary2.netlify.app/authors/admin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mary2.netlify.app/authors/admin/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Church of Holy Name of Mary has existed for more than 127 years. It was built by Fr. Michael Seet in over 3 years period with overwhelming support and cooperation from the parishioners.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="the-lord-the-god-of-heaven-has-given-me-all-the-kingdoms-of-the-earth-and-he-has-appointed-me-to-build-a-temple-for-him-at-jerusalem-in-judah-any-of-his-people-among-you-may-go-up-and-may-the-lord-their-god-be-with-them---2-chronicles-3623">&amp;ldquo;The LORD, the God of heaven, has given me all the kingdoms of the earth and he has appointed me to build a temple for him at Jerusalem in Judah. Any of his people among you may go up, and may the LORD their God be with them.&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong>- 2 Chronicles 36:23&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The church was based on Gothic architecture design originated from France which often features spires, pinnacles, decorative sculptures, large windows which have tracery such as rose window and window with stained glass. A characteristic of Gothic Church is its height, the verticality suggesting an aspiration to Heaven.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the main building structures were built and designed locally such as the spire, unique spiral staircase, the tracery pattern ceiling and the rose windows. The bell tower together with the spire is 90 feet high. The spire was constructed with hard wood and plank. The asbestos ceiling was painted with distemper of different colours.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>