<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Church of The Holy Name of Mary</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Church of The Holy Name of Mary</description><generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} Church of The Holy Name of Mary Permatang Tinggi</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Matthew 8:1-4</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-1-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-1-4/</guid><description>&lt;figure >
&lt;audio id="player" controls>
&lt;source src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/audio/en/matthew8-1-4.mp3" type="audio/mp3">
&lt;/audio>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="gospel">Gospel&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus came down from the mountainside, large crowds followed him. A man with leprosy came and knelt before him and said, “Lord, if you are willing, you can make me clean.” Jesus reached out his hand and touched the man. “I am willing,” he said. “Be clean!” Immediately he was cleansed of his leprosy. Then Jesus said to him, “See that you don’t tell anyone. But go, show yourself to the priest and offer the gift Moses commanded, as a testimony to them.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In our key Scripture for today, Jesus healed a leper instantly by touching him. Contrary to the beliefs of the time, Jesus did not contract any ritual uncleanness. Leprosy was one of the diseases that was considered physically and spiritually ugly and excludes the sufferer from the community and most importantly, from the houses of worship.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mortal sin is analogous to leprosy. It is God&amp;rsquo;s merciful Providence that humans do not see the soul.
The One who touched the lepers and healed them is still among us. He heals every day the most important ailment of man, sin. He does this through the Sacrament of Penance. A good Confession restores the soul fully to sanctifying grace. Sanctifying grace is the life of God in the soul. The soul becomes once again the home of the Holy Spirit. Who cannot be moved by the words of Jesus below to a Benedictine mystic?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>