<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Church of Holy Name of Mary</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Church of Holy Name of Mary</description><generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} Church of The Holy Name of Mary Permatang Tinggi</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>John 20:24-29</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/john20-24-29/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/john20-24-29/</guid><description>&lt;figure >
&lt;audio id="player" controls>
&lt;source src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/audio/en/john20-24-29.mp3" type="audio/mp3">
&lt;/audio>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="gospel">Gospel&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Now Thomas (also known as Didymus), one of the Twelve, was not with the disciples when Jesus came. So the other disciples told him, “We have seen the Lord!” But he said to them, “Unless I see the nail marks in his hands and put my finger where the nails were, and put my hand into his side, I will not believe.” A week later his disciples were in the house again, and Thomas was with them. Though the doors were locked, Jesus came and stood among them and said, “Peace be with you!” Then he said to Thomas, “Put your finger here; see my hands. Reach out your hand and put it into my side. Stop doubting and believe.” Thomas said to him, “My Lord and my God!” Then Jesus told him, “Because you have seen me, you have believed; blessed are those who have not seen and yet have believed.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It’s Sunday and the disciples have assembled together. The disciples had met the Sunday before but Thomas wasn’t with them. Thomas wasn’t there when Jesus appeared to them. The disciples shared the good news of Jesus’ resurrection but Thomas said to them, “Unless I see the nail marks in his hands and put my finger where the nails were, and put my hand into his side, I will not believe.” (John 20:25)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Too bad Thomas missed that meeting. Had he made it, he would have experienced the bodily presence of Jesus and believed a week early. His doubt would have been erased and his faith would have been increased. But because Thomas missed that last meeting his doubt endured.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You know, if you think about it, something similar happened when Jesus appeared to the 500 after the resurrection. 1 Corinthians 15:6 tells us there were 500 present when Jesus commanded them, “Do not leave Jerusalem, but wait for the gift my Father promised… …in a few days you will be baptized with the Holy Spirit.” (Acts 1:4-5)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet in Acts 1:15 it appears that only 120 of them listened and obeyed Jesus’ words. That’s huge! That means 380 missed the meeting in the upper room described in Acts 1:15. That also means 380 missed out on the blessing of the Holy Spirit. 120 had tongues of fire on their heads and spoke powerfully in foreign languages they didn’t know. 120 were used to save the souls of 3,000 people. (Acts chapter 2) 380 were left out–because they missed the meeting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Verse 24 of John 20 says that Thomas was also known as Didymus. Didymus means twin in the Greek, so who’s twin is he?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He’s the twin of you and he’s the twin of me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have you ever missed a meeting with the Lord? I know I have. Missing meetings means missing out. Missing out on experiencing fellowship with the body of Christ. Missing out on believing. Missing out on increased faith. Had Thomas made it to the first meeting he would have seen Jesus and believed. His doubt would have been erased and his faith would have been increased!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s what happens to us when we make meetings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because Thomas missed the last meeting his doubt endured. It’s the same with you and the same with me. When we miss meetings, when we miss hearing the word of God whatever doubts we have endure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No doubt Thomas and the 380 had their reasons for missing. They worked hard all week so they were too tired, or they didn’t care for someone who they knew would be attending that meeting, or there was a good game on TV that morning. But whatever their reason, when they missed the meeting they missed out on experiencing the presence of Jesus in a unique way. They missed out on the empowerment of the Holy Spirit. They missed out on a tremendous blessing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh twin of doubting Thomas, don’t you see that Thomas didn’t believe until he touched Jesus? Don’t you see it’s the same for you today? You won’t believe until you touch Him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So touch him. Study Jesus’ life in the scriptures. Encounter Jesus with His believers. Do these things and you too will believe! Like Thomas, you too will find yourself responding to him, saying, “My Lord and my God!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You’ll never regret it, I promise you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Make the meeting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Go to church.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qj4bt2kgJlY" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Matthew 9:9-13</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew9-9-13/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew9-9-13/</guid><description>&lt;figure >
&lt;audio id="player" controls>
&lt;source src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/audio/en/matthew9-9-13.mp3" type="audio/mp3">
&lt;/audio>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="gospel">Gospel&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>As Jesus went on from there, he saw a man named Matthew sitting at the tax collector’s booth. “Follow me,” he told him, and Matthew got up and followed him. While Jesus was having dinner at Matthew’s house, many tax collectors and sinners came and ate with him and his disciples. When the Pharisees saw this, they asked his disciples, “Why does your teacher eat with tax collectors and sinners?” On hearing this, Jesus said, “It is not the healthy who need a doctor, but the sick. But go and learn what this means: ‘I desire mercy, not sacrifice.’ For I have not come to call the righteous, but sinners.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/re7Q6Gmi4Vk" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Aside from Matthew whom Jesus called to follow Him we too are being called by the Lord. We may say that we are not worthy to follow Jesus but who amongst us are worthy? No one for we are all sinful creatures of this world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matthew was called by Jesus to follow Him for the precise reason that he was a sinner. This is the character and mission of Jesus to call every sinner to follow Him. But why is it that even if we know that we are called to repentance we still continue to sin? We refuse to leave behind us our sinful ways.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is indeed very puzzling, why is it that many of us ignore Jesus call for us to follow Him? Does this mean that we love this world more than we love Jesus? Does this mean that Jesus is losing influence over us and the devil is slowly but surely gaining control of our lives that is why we refuse to heed Jesus’ call to a life of renewal and repentance?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why did Matthew follow Jesus call? Perhaps somebody had shared to him the love and unfathomable mercy of Jesus. Somebody had lived his faith in Jesus and Matthew heard and saw it, that’s why it was not anymore difficult for Matthew to recognize and follow Jesus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The challenge before us is to share and live our faith in Jesus to the many Matthews (Sinners) of our time. They may not have heard yet anything about Jesus that is why they keep on sinning until this very day. Why not share the mercy and love of Jesus?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Would you share Jesus?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Matthew 9:1-8</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew9-1-8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew9-1-8/</guid><description>&lt;figure >
&lt;audio id="player" controls>
&lt;source src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/audio/en/matthew9-1-8.mp3" type="audio/mp3">
&lt;/audio>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="gospel">Gospel&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Jesus stepped into a boat, crossed over and came to his own town. Some men brought to him a paralyzed man, lying on a mat. When Jesus saw their faith, he said to the man, “Take heart, son; your sins are forgiven.” At this, some of the teachers of the law said to themselves, “This fellow is blaspheming!” Knowing their thoughts, Jesus said, “Why do you entertain evil thoughts in your hearts? Which is easier: to say, ‘Your sins are forgiven,’ or to say, ‘Get up and walk’? But I want you to know that the Son of Man has authority on earth to forgive sins.” So he said to the paralyzed man, “Get up, take your mat and go home.” Then the man got up and went home. When the crowd saw this, they were filled with awe; and they praised God, who had given such authority to man.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Uar4u9CcA74" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>What cripples the mind and heart and stiffles the healing power of love? Sin and unforgiveness for certain! Sin cripples us more than any physical ailment can. Sin is the work of the kingdom of darkness and it holds us in eternal bondage. There is only one solution and that is the healing, cleansing power of Jesus' forgiveness. Jesus’ treatment of sinners upset the religious teachers of the day. When a cripple was brought to Jesus because of the faith of his friends, Jesus did the unthinkable. He first forgave the man his sins. The scribes regarded this as blasphemy because they understood that only God had authority to forgive sins and to unbind a man or woman from their burden of guilt. Jesus claimed an authority which only God could rightfully give. Jesus not only proved that his authority came from God, he showed the great power of God&amp;rsquo;s redeeming love and mercy by healing the cripple of his physical ailment. This man had been crippled not only physically, but spiritually as well. Jesus freed him from his burden of guilt and restored his body as well. The Lord is every ready to bring us healing of mind, body, and soul. His grace brings us freedom from the power of sin and from bondage to harmful desires and addictions. Do you allow anything to keep you from Jesus' healing power?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Lord Jesus, through your merciful love and forgiveness you bring healing and restoration to body, soul, and mind. May your healing power and love touch every area of my life &amp;ndash; my innermost thoughts, feelings, attitudes, and memories. Pardon my offences and transform me in the power of your Holy Spirit that I may walk confidently in your truth and righteousness.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Matthew 8:28-32</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-28-32/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-28-32/</guid><description>&lt;figure >
&lt;audio id="player" controls>
&lt;source src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/audio/en/matthew8-28-32.mp3" type="audio/mp3">
&lt;/audio>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="gospel">Gospel&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When He had come to the other side, to the country of the Gergesenes, there met Him two demon-possessed men, coming out of the tombs, exceedingly fierce, so that no one could pass that way. And suddenly they cried out, saying, “What have we to do with You, Jesus, You Son of God? Have You come here to torment us before the time?” Now a good way off from them there was a herd of many swine feeding. So the demons begged Him, saying, “If You cast us out, permit us to go away into the herd of swine.” And He said to them, “Go.” So when they had come out, they went into the herd of swine. And suddenly the whole herd of swine ran violently down the steep place into the sea, and perished in the water.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Here is a picture of our Lord, who rescues us. He just went through a storm to cross a sea most would not dare to tread, to a place few would ever go, to see two people who needed His help. One would reject Him and one would beg to go with Him, while the community who rejected these two people also rejected Christ, and demanded His departure, as they valued pigs over people, money over eternity. This passage stresses the point that Jesus is no mere man; He is divine. Even the demons testify to this!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a strange story from a godly perspective, as the people who should have marveled at Jesus' ability to heal two people whom they had given up on, saw a divine miracle preformed before them, and benefited by being saved from the torment of the demons, only to demand that He leave. Yet, so many of us do the same thing every day. We may know of the Lord, even experienced His grace, maybe even have served Him for a time, yet, we too, ask Him to go away. We sometimes do not allow Him in all parts and times of our lives. Maybe we let Him in just on Sunday morning, but not on Monday, and definitely not on Friday nights. So, do you ask Jesus to leave, or allow Him to endear and embrace you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How sad it is that as the demons cried out &amp;ldquo;this is none of your business,&amp;rdquo; we too make such heinous proclamations to the very Lord who crossed a storm to redeem us! He who bridged the gap of sin we could never cross, paved the Way for our salvation and sanctification. He allows us to remain in the boat with Him, even calling us to go with Him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do not fall into compliancy and arrogance, seeing no need for our Lord, ignoring His call to you, thinking you are all right, because if you are honest, you are not all right! Do not allow yourself to be filled with so much busyness that you have no time for Him! Do not be like the village people who saw the pigs as of more value than people. If you say, &amp;ldquo;Well, I have no pigs.&amp;rdquo; consider that you do in the way of what is of value to you. Does it line up with His values and call? What about your career&amp;ndash;even ministry? Is it more important than your growth in Christ, so your real service of building quality relationships gets pushed aside? Jesus will not force Himself upon you, as He did not with those village people. The call is given. Your sin has been covered. It is up to you to now follow!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Matthew 16:13-19</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew16-13-19/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew16-13-19/</guid><description>&lt;figure >
&lt;audio id="player" controls>
&lt;source src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/audio/en/matthew16-13-19.mp3" type="audio/mp3">
&lt;/audio>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="gospel">Gospel&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus came to the region of Caesarea Philippi, he asked his disciples, “Who do people say the Son of Man is?” They replied, “Some say John the Baptist; others say Elijah; and still others, Jeremiah or one of the prophets.” “But what about you?” he asked. “Who do you say I am?” Simon Peter answered, “You are the Messiah, the Son of the living God.” Jesus replied, “Blessed are you, Simon son of Jonah, for this was not revealed to you by flesh and blood, but by my Father in heaven. And I tell you that you are Peter, and on this rock I will build my church, and the gates of Hades will not overcome it. I will give you the keys of the kingdom of heaven; whatever you bind on earth will be bound in heaven, and whatever you loose on earth will be loosed in heaven.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tbsa86CysJw" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Why honor Saints Peter and Paul with a Solemnity? Because the most important accomplishment of Jesus Christ in His mission on earth is the CHURCH! The Church is the Sacrament and Instrument of SALVATION for all mankind. Scripture teaches that the Church is built on the foundation of the Apostles and Prophets. (Cf Ephesians 2: 20). Peter and Paul are joint managing directors of the institution, which is called the Church.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;You are Peter and upon this rock I will build my church, and the gates of the netherworld shall not prevail against it.&amp;rdquo; (Matthew 16: 18)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Paul got his mandate to be an Apostle directly from Jesus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Now I want you to know, brothers, that the gospel preached by me is not of human origin. For I did not receive it from a human being, nor was I taught it, but it came through a revelation of Jesus Christ.&amp;rdquo; (Galatians 1: 11 - 12).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peter and Paul were called to be friends and companions of Jesus before anything else.
&amp;ldquo;I ask you only to be My friend and to live at every moment in the grace of My divine friendship. All the rest follows. Perfection is the fruit of friendship with Me, not a precondition for it. You, and many souls like you, are confused about this. My friendship is not earned, it is not something acquired by measuring up to the standards of perfection that you have set for yourself. My friendship is pure gift.&amp;rdquo; (IN SINU JESU).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peter and Paul are the ones who, living in the flesh, planted the Church with their blood;
they drank the chalice of the Lord and became the friends of God.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Matthew 8:18-22</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-18-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-18-22/</guid><description>&lt;figure >
&lt;audio id="player" controls>
&lt;source src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/audio/en/matthew8-18-22.mp3" type="audio/mp3">
&lt;/audio>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="gospel">Gospel&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus saw the crowd around him, he gave orders to cross to the other side of the lake. Then a teacher of the law came to him and said, “Teacher, I will follow you wherever you go.” Jesus replied, “Foxes have dens and birds have nests, but the Son of Man has no place to lay his head.” Another disciple said to him, “Lord, first let me go and bury my father.” But Jesus told him, “Follow me, and let the dead bury their own dead.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Bishop and Martyr. St Polycarp was instructed in the faith by St John the Apostle. He, Polycarp instructed St Irenaeus who became a Bishop in France. He is an early Church Father. God called Irenaeus to uphold the revealed truth of the faith and bring peace to the Church.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are you called to serve the Lord? The marching order is intimidating. Don&amp;rsquo;t waste time about who died and burial rites. “Follow me, and let the dead bury their dead.” On another occasion, Jesus commanded the disciples: &amp;ldquo;More than anything else, put God’s work first and do what he wants. Then the other things will be yours as well.&amp;rdquo; (Matthew 6: 33 CEV).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>St Irenaeus, Bishop and Martyr and Father of the Church did not play games with the truths of the holy Faith. He studied what Christ our Teacher handed down to us. For example, the Eucharist. His bold, clear and unambiguous teaching was respected even by foes and he brought peace to the Church. One of Irenaeus famous quotes is: &amp;ldquo;The glory of God is man fully alive.&amp;rdquo; God is glorified when we develop our talents to the utmost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I want you to speak to the faithful of the Holy Mass as a true sacrifice. They have forgotten this. No one thinks any more to tell them that the action of the Eucharist renews My sacrifice upon the Cross, and that I am present upon the altar as upon the Cross, as both Priest and Victim. It is the whole of My sacrifice of love that unfolds before their eyes. You must tell them this.&amp;rdquo; (Jesus to a Benedictine mystic: IN SINU JESU).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By the prayers of St Irenaeus, may God renew our faith and love for the Most Holy Eucharist.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Happy 74th Birthday to Fr Augustine Wong</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/happy-birthday-to-fr-augustine-wong/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/happy-birthday-to-fr-augustine-wong/</guid><description>&lt;p>The church would like to greet a Happy Birthday to our former Parish Priest of Fr Augustine Wong. He has been appointed as Parish Priest to Church of The Holy Name of Mary Permatang Tinggi from Jan 2011 until arch 2021. Almost for a decade he has served his entire service to the community, and the church an finally retired last March. At the moment, he is staying in Taman Permatang Tinggi Indah. We pray to the Lord that Fr Wong has a peaceful and joyful day for the rest of his life.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="gallery">
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/happy-birthday-to-fr-augustine-wong/gallery/2.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/happy-birthday-to-fr-augustine-wong/gallery/2_hu09ba136233ef9add2b320b487975ccf6_39357_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/happy-birthday-to-fr-augustine-wong/gallery/3.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/happy-birthday-to-fr-augustine-wong/gallery/3_hu8544f822b13f685289d9332f3beac8d1_133244_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/happy-birthday-to-fr-augustine-wong/gallery/4.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/happy-birthday-to-fr-augustine-wong/gallery/4_hu96f2e703fc93ac1a2c807a133adfbcc3_76793_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;a data-fancybox="gallery-gallery" href="https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/happy-birthday-to-fr-augustine-wong/gallery/4b.jpg" >
&lt;img src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/happy-birthday-to-fr-augustine-wong/gallery/4b_hu3e3aa75d4900640c49fc3f8d1b490942_54866_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="黄炳隆神父在本堂的事迹">黄炳隆神父在本堂的事迹：&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Rename the graveyard to &amp;lsquo;All Saints Paradise&amp;rsquo;，repair and reconstruct the wall as well as the entrance.
&lt;img src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/img/post/grave.jpg" alt="All Saints Paradise">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Launching of &amp;lsquo;Fundraising for New Church&amp;rsquo; to build a new temple of worship next to existing church.
&lt;img src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/img/post/newchurch.jpg" alt="Launching of &amp;lsquo;Fundraising for New Church&amp;rsquo;">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Established Legion of Mary。
&lt;img src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/img/post/legionofmary.jpg" alt="Legion of Mary">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Established BEC team
&lt;img src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/img/post/bec.jpg" alt="BEC">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Established St Mark Lion dance group
&lt;img src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/img/post/liondanceclub.jpg" alt="St Mark Lion dance group">&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="who-is-st-john-vianney">Who is St John Vianney&lt;/h3>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bu_FfYL_XJ0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Mark 8:21-43</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/mark8-21-43/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/mark8-21-43/</guid><description>&lt;figure >
&lt;audio id="player" controls>
&lt;source src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/audio/en/mark8-21-43.mp3" type="audio/mp3">
&lt;/audio>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="gospel">Gospel&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus had again crossed over by boat to the other side of the lake, a large crowd gathered around him while he was by the lake. Then one of the synagogue leaders, named Jairus, came, and when he saw Jesus, he fell at his feet. He pleaded earnestly with him, “My little daughter is dying. Please come and put your hands on her so that she will be healed and live.” So Jesus went with him.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A large crowd followed and pressed around him. And a woman was there who had been subject to bleeding for twelve years. She had suffered a great deal under the care of many doctors and had spent all she had, yet instead of getting better she grew worse. When she heard about Jesus, she came up behind him in the crowd and touched his cloak, because she thought, “If I just touch his clothes, I will be healed.” Immediately her bleeding stopped and she felt in her body that she was freed from her suffering.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>At once Jesus realized that power had gone out from him. He turned around in the crowd and asked, “Who touched my clothes?” “You see the people crowding against you,” his disciples answered, “and yet you can ask, ‘Who touched me?’ ” But Jesus kept looking around to see who had done it. Then the woman, knowing what had happened to her, came and fell at his feet and, trembling with fear, told him the whole truth. He said to her, “Daughter, your faith has healed you. Go in peace and be freed from your suffering.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>While Jesus was still speaking, some people came from the house of Jairus, the synagogue leader. “Your daughter is dead,” they said. “Why bother the teacher anymore?” Overhearing what they said, Jesus told him, “Don’t be afraid; just believe.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>He did not let anyone follow him except Peter, James and John the brother of James. When they came to the home of the synagogue leader, Jesus saw a commotion, with people crying and wailing loudly. He went in and said to them, “Why all this commotion and wailing? The child is not dead but asleep.” But they laughed at him.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>After he put them all out, he took the child’s father and mother and the disciples who were with him, and went in where the child was. He took her by the hand and said to her, “Talitha koum!” (which means “Little girl, I say to you, get up!”). Immediately the girl stood up and began to walk around (she was twelve years old). At this they were completely astonished. He gave strict orders not to let anyone know about this, and told them to give her something to eat.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="sermon">Sermon&lt;/h3>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1PKmLY7F94E" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Gospel for the 13th Sunday in Ordinary Time contains two important stories about the importance of faith in healing:
Woman with a Hemorrhage and Jairus’s Daughter. The afflicted woman and Jairus had heard about Jesus before they sought Him out and encountered the Lord.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jesus praised the faith of the woman. “Daughter, your faith has saved you. Go in peace and be cured of your affliction.” When the crowd wanted to pour cold water on the faith of Jairus, Jesus said to him: “Do not be afraid; just have faith.” I like how one translation renders this: &amp;ldquo;Fear is useless. What is needed is trust.&amp;rdquo; When Jairus heard this, his faith was strengthened. Jesus went into the house where He took the child by the hand and said to her, “Talitha koum,” which means, “Little girl, I say to you, arise!” The girl, a child of twelve, arose immediately and walked around. At that they were utterly astounded.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your trust in Jesus is in direct proportion to your awareness of who He is and how much He has done for you.
&amp;ldquo;Love Me and believe in My unconditional love for you. Trust Me. Show Me that you have confidence in My merciful goodness, especially when you experience weakness, or shame, or fear, and I will renew the grace of My love in your heart. I will uphold you with the gift of My unfailing presence.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Matthew 8:5-17</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-5-17/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-5-17/</guid><description>&lt;figure >
&lt;audio id="player" controls>
&lt;source src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/audio/en/matthew8-5-17.mp3" type="audio/mp3">
&lt;/audio>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="gospel">Gospel&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus had entered Capernaum, a centurion came to him, asking for help. “Lord,” he said, “my servant lies at home paralyzed, suffering terribly.” Jesus said to him, “Shall I come and heal him?” The centurion replied, “Lord, I do not deserve to have you come under my roof. But just say the word, and my servant will be healed. For I myself am a man under authority, with soldiers under me. I tell this one, ‘Go,’ and he goes; and that one, ‘Come,’ and he comes. I say to my servant, ‘Do this,’ and he does it.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus heard this, he was amazed and said to those following him, “Truly I tell you, I have not found anyone in Israel with such great faith. I say to you that many will come from the east and the west, and will take their places at the feast with Abraham, Isaac and Jacob in the kingdom of heaven. But the subjects of the kingdom will be thrown outside, into the darkness, where there will be weeping and gnashing of teeth.” Then Jesus said to the centurion, “Go! Let it be done just as you believed it would.” And his servant was healed at that moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus came into Peter’s house, he saw Peter’s mother-in-law lying in bed with a fever. He touched her hand and the fever left her, and she got up and began to wait on him. When evening came, many who were demon-possessed were brought to him, and he drove out the spirits with a word and healed all the sick. This was to fulfill what was spoken through the prophet Isaiah: “He took up our infirmities and bore our diseases.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="sermon">Sermon&lt;/h3>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/leaA9RqU3l4" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>What kind of expectant faith and trust does the Lord Jesus want you to place in him? In Jesus' time the Jews hated the Romans because they represented everything the Jews stood against - including pagan beliefs and idol worship, immoral practices such as abortion and infanticide, and the suppression of the Israelites' claim to be a holy nation governed solely by God&amp;rsquo;s law. It must have been a remarkable sight for the Jewish residents of Capernaum to see Jesus conversing with an officer of the Roman army.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="the-power-to-command-with-trust-and-respect">The power to command with trust and respect&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Why did Jesus not only warmly receive a Roman centurion but praise him as a model of faith and confidence in God? In the Roman world the position of centurion was very important. He was an officer in charge of a hundred soldiers. In a certain sense, he was the backbone of the Roman army, the cement which held the army together. Polybius, an ancient write, describes what a centurion should be: &amp;ldquo;They must not be so much venturesome seekers after danger as men who can command, steady in action, and reliable; they ought not to be over-anxious to rush into the fight, but when hard pressed, they must be ready to hold their ground, and die at their posts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="faith-in-jesus-authority-over-sickness-and-power-to-heal">Faith in Jesus' authority over sickness and power to heal&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The centurion who approached Jesus was not only courageous, but faith-filled as well. He risked the ridicule of his Roman cronies (close friends of someone in a powerful position) by seeking help from a traveling preacher from Galilee, as well as mockery from the Jews who despised their Roman overlords. Nonetheless, the centurion approached Jesus with great respect and confidence. He was an extraordinary man because he loved his slave. In the Roman world slaves were treated as property and like animals rather than people. The centurion was an extraordinary man of faith and love. He wanted Jesus to heal his beloved slave. Jesus commends him for his faith and immediately grants him his request. Are you willing to suffer mockery or ridicule in the practice of your faith? And when you in need of help, do you approach the Lord Jesus with expectant faith and trust?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Heavenly Father, you sent us your only begotten Son, our Lord Jesus Christ, to set us free from sin, pride, and Satan&amp;rsquo;s lies. Set me free from doubt and pride so that I may trust in your all-powerful word of truth and life. Strengthen me in faith, hope, and love so that I may always think, act and serve in the power of your merciful kindness and compassion towards all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Matthew 8:1-4</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-1-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-1-4/</guid><description>&lt;figure >
&lt;audio id="player" controls>
&lt;source src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/audio/en/matthew8-1-4.mp3" type="audio/mp3">
&lt;/audio>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="gospel">Gospel&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus came down from the mountainside, large crowds followed him. A man with leprosy came and knelt before him and said, “Lord, if you are willing, you can make me clean.” Jesus reached out his hand and touched the man. “I am willing,” he said. “Be clean!” Immediately he was cleansed of his leprosy. Then Jesus said to him, “See that you don’t tell anyone. But go, show yourself to the priest and offer the gift Moses commanded, as a testimony to them.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In our key Scripture for today, Jesus healed a leper instantly by touching him. Contrary to the beliefs of the time, Jesus did not contract any ritual uncleanness. Leprosy was one of the diseases that was considered physically and spiritually ugly and excludes the sufferer from the community and most importantly, from the houses of worship.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mortal sin is analogous to leprosy. It is God&amp;rsquo;s merciful Providence that humans do not see the soul.
The One who touched the lepers and healed them is still among us. He heals every day the most important ailment of man, sin. He does this through the Sacrament of Penance. A good Confession restores the soul fully to sanctifying grace. Sanctifying grace is the life of God in the soul. The soul becomes once again the home of the Holy Spirit. Who cannot be moved by the words of Jesus below to a Benedictine mystic?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>