<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Church of The Holy Name of Mary</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Church of The Holy Name of Mary</description><generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} Church of The Holy Name of Mary Permatang Tinggi</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Matthew 8:5-17</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-5-17/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-5-17/</guid><description>&lt;figure >
&lt;audio id="player" controls>
&lt;source src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/audio/en/matthew8-5-17.mp3" type="audio/mp3">
&lt;/audio>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="gospel">Gospel&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus had entered Capernaum, a centurion came to him, asking for help. “Lord,” he said, “my servant lies at home paralyzed, suffering terribly.” Jesus said to him, “Shall I come and heal him?” The centurion replied, “Lord, I do not deserve to have you come under my roof. But just say the word, and my servant will be healed. For I myself am a man under authority, with soldiers under me. I tell this one, ‘Go,’ and he goes; and that one, ‘Come,’ and he comes. I say to my servant, ‘Do this,’ and he does it.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus heard this, he was amazed and said to those following him, “Truly I tell you, I have not found anyone in Israel with such great faith. I say to you that many will come from the east and the west, and will take their places at the feast with Abraham, Isaac and Jacob in the kingdom of heaven. But the subjects of the kingdom will be thrown outside, into the darkness, where there will be weeping and gnashing of teeth.” Then Jesus said to the centurion, “Go! Let it be done just as you believed it would.” And his servant was healed at that moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus came into Peter’s house, he saw Peter’s mother-in-law lying in bed with a fever. He touched her hand and the fever left her, and she got up and began to wait on him. When evening came, many who were demon-possessed were brought to him, and he drove out the spirits with a word and healed all the sick. This was to fulfill what was spoken through the prophet Isaiah: “He took up our infirmities and bore our diseases.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="sermon">Sermon&lt;/h3>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/leaA9RqU3l4" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>What kind of expectant faith and trust does the Lord Jesus want you to place in him? In Jesus' time the Jews hated the Romans because they represented everything the Jews stood against - including pagan beliefs and idol worship, immoral practices such as abortion and infanticide, and the suppression of the Israelites' claim to be a holy nation governed solely by God&amp;rsquo;s law. It must have been a remarkable sight for the Jewish residents of Capernaum to see Jesus conversing with an officer of the Roman army.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="the-power-to-command-with-trust-and-respect">The power to command with trust and respect&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Why did Jesus not only warmly receive a Roman centurion but praise him as a model of faith and confidence in God? In the Roman world the position of centurion was very important. He was an officer in charge of a hundred soldiers. In a certain sense, he was the backbone of the Roman army, the cement which held the army together. Polybius, an ancient write, describes what a centurion should be: &amp;ldquo;They must not be so much venturesome seekers after danger as men who can command, steady in action, and reliable; they ought not to be over-anxious to rush into the fight, but when hard pressed, they must be ready to hold their ground, and die at their posts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="faith-in-jesus-authority-over-sickness-and-power-to-heal">Faith in Jesus' authority over sickness and power to heal&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The centurion who approached Jesus was not only courageous, but faith-filled as well. He risked the ridicule of his Roman cronies (close friends of someone in a powerful position) by seeking help from a traveling preacher from Galilee, as well as mockery from the Jews who despised their Roman overlords. Nonetheless, the centurion approached Jesus with great respect and confidence. He was an extraordinary man because he loved his slave. In the Roman world slaves were treated as property and like animals rather than people. The centurion was an extraordinary man of faith and love. He wanted Jesus to heal his beloved slave. Jesus commends him for his faith and immediately grants him his request. Are you willing to suffer mockery or ridicule in the practice of your faith? And when you in need of help, do you approach the Lord Jesus with expectant faith and trust?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Heavenly Father, you sent us your only begotten Son, our Lord Jesus Christ, to set us free from sin, pride, and Satan&amp;rsquo;s lies. Set me free from doubt and pride so that I may trust in your all-powerful word of truth and life. Strengthen me in faith, hope, and love so that I may always think, act and serve in the power of your merciful kindness and compassion towards all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Matthew 8:1-4</title><link>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-1-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://holynameofmarypt.com/en/post/matthew8-1-4/</guid><description>&lt;figure >
&lt;audio id="player" controls>
&lt;source src="https://holynameofmarypt.com/audio/en/matthew8-1-4.mp3" type="audio/mp3">
&lt;/audio>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="gospel">Gospel&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Jesus came down from the mountainside, large crowds followed him. A man with leprosy came and knelt before him and said, “Lord, if you are willing, you can make me clean.” Jesus reached out his hand and touched the man. “I am willing,” he said. “Be clean!” Immediately he was cleansed of his leprosy. Then Jesus said to him, “See that you don’t tell anyone. But go, show yourself to the priest and offer the gift Moses commanded, as a testimony to them.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="reflection">Reflection&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In our key Scripture for today, Jesus healed a leper instantly by touching him. Contrary to the beliefs of the time, Jesus did not contract any ritual uncleanness. Leprosy was one of the diseases that was considered physically and spiritually ugly and excludes the sufferer from the community and most importantly, from the houses of worship.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mortal sin is analogous to leprosy. It is God&amp;rsquo;s merciful Providence that humans do not see the soul.
The One who touched the lepers and healed them is still among us. He heals every day the most important ailment of man, sin. He does this through the Sacrament of Penance. A good Confession restores the soul fully to sanctifying grace. Sanctifying grace is the life of God in the soul. The soul becomes once again the home of the Holy Spirit. Who cannot be moved by the words of Jesus below to a Benedictine mystic?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>